斯坦福大学
> Stanford University.
欢迎来到 CS193P 课程 2013-14 秋季第 15 讲
> Okay. Well, welcome to lecture 15 of CS193p for fall of 2013/14.
今天的主要内容将是 MapKit
And our primary topic today is going to be the map kit,
也就是我们周一讨论的那种 UI
which is kind of the UI on what we talked about on Monday.
作为这个的一部分 特别是在演示中
As part of that, though, especially in the demonstration
我会展示关于 segue 的两点重要内容
that I do, I'm going to show you two things about segue's that are pretty important.
一是如何从代码中发起 segue
One is how to fire off a segue from code.
之前 我们一直都是通过
So far all the time that we've made a segue go,
从故事板的一处 control 拖动到
we just control, dragged from something in a storyboard
另一个故事板 然后我们再点击它
to another storyboard, and then we clicked on that something.
得到 segue 下面我们将考虑从代码中发起 segue
It would segue, so now we're going to able to fire off a segue from in code.
然后我今天还会讲到一种新的 segue
And then I'm also going to teach you a new kind of segue today,
也就是 embed segue 这个我也会演示
which is the embed segue, and I'm going to demo that, as well,
我有一个大的 demo 演示各种地图方面的内容
in a big demo that shows you all the map stuff
还有手动 segue 和 embed segue
and manual segue and the embed segue.
以上就是今天的内容
So that's what's on tap for today.
来看 MapKit
And, so, map kit.
MapKit 是什么
So what is map kit?
MapKit 也就是位置的用户界面
Map kit is basically user interface for locations
它主要的类是这个 UIView 叫作 MKMapView
and its primary class is this UI view, called an MK map view.
MapView 这整个属于一个不同的框架 叫 MapKit 框架
The whole map view stuff is in a different framework, called a map kit framework.
想使用 MapKit 框架时
When you want to use the map kit framework you have
你需要明确到项目设置中进行关联
to actually explicitly go into your project settings and set it to be linked.
否则 MKMapView 这些类都不会有
Otherwise, all these classes like MK map view won't be there,
我会在 demo 中演示如何做到这个
and I'm going to show that in the demo, how you do that.
在 MapView 之内 有这些大头针
So, inside of the map view, you have these little pins.
这些大头针可以有不同颜色
They look a little red pin there, they can be different colors.
这些被叫作 AnnotationView
These are called annotation views.
你可以自定义 可以创建 AnnotationView 的子类
So every annotation view in there, and you,
you can customize this, you can subclass annotation view
你也可以让它不是一个大头针
to make it not look like a pin if you want.
反正 这些 AnnotationView 负责
But these annotation views are responsible
显示世界中的某个地点
for showing some place in the world,
除了大头针以外
and they have a pin,
这里还有一个对话框
but then they also have this little call out, if you click
点击时 这里会有一个白条
on them, you see that little white bar right there?
这个对话框也可以自定义
And that call out can be customized, a little bit.
可以设置标题和副标题
The title that's in it and it can have a little subtitle
它还可以有左侧和右侧的附属视图
and also it can have left and right accessory views,
这里有一个左附属视图 这是一个图像视图
so this one has a left accessory view, which is an image view,
还有一个右附属视图 这是一个按钮 你可以点它
and there's a right accessory view which is a little button that you can click on.
demo 中 所有这些部分我们都会演示
So in our demo we're going to do all of this.
And we're going to cover all of these various parts, what's going on.
主要需要理解的是 如何创建 MapView
But the main thing to understand is how you create a map view
以及如何将这些东西放到地图上
and how you put these things on the map, so map view,
MapView 可以 alloc init
just alloc init, or more often
不过更常用的方法是从 Xcode 的面板中拖出
we drag it out, from the palette, in Xcode,
要想使用大头针 我们需要加上这些 Annotation
and the way we put the pins on there is we add these things called annotations.
Annotation 其实就是一个 id 响应这个协议
So an annotation is really just an ID, the response to this protocol.
这个 MKAnnotation 协议
See this MK annotation protocol up here.
应用程序中任何响应这个协议的对象
So any object in your entire application that responds to this protocol
都可以被放到 MapView 上
can just be dropped onto the map view.
这个协议中有什么呢
So what's in this protocol?
很简单 它有一些可选方法 标题和副标题
Very simple, it's got a couple optional methods, the title and subtitle,
我们看到的那个白色对话框
so in that little white call out that we saw,
那里有标题和副标题
that's going to be the title and subtitle there.
然后它有一个很重要的必须属性 也就是坐标
And then it's got a very important required property, which is the coordinate.
坐标也就是经纬度
So the coordinate is just the latitude and longitude,
由 CLLocation 坐标指定 这是 C struct
as specified by this CL location coordinate, C struct.
任何能够回答这些的对象
And so any object that can answer these,
其实主要也就是坐标这个问题
really just this one question of the coordinate,
不过通常 我们也需要标题和副标题
but usually we want title and subtitle too,
都能被放到地图上
can be thrown on a map,
例如 在我们的 demo 中
and, for example, in the demo that we're going to do,
我们会扩展 Photomania
we're going to extend photo mania.
我会被照片对象放到那里
I'm just going to throw photo objects in there.
实际上 照片对象已经实现了标题和副标题
In fact, photo objects already implement title and subtitle,
我们只需要让照片对象成为 MKAnnotation
so all we really need to do is make a photo object be an MK annotation
并响应那个协议
and respond to that protocol,
只需要实现坐标方法
is to implement the required coordinate method and that's what we're going to do
照片就能放到地图上了
and then we can just throw photos on the map.
这里不需要任何特殊的类
We don't have to make any other special classes or anything,
只需要把照片丢到地图上
just throw the photos themselves up there.
设定 Annotation 时 这个属性…
When you're setting the annotations, this property,
MKMapView 上有一个属性是 Annotation 的 NSArray
there's a property on MK map view which is an NS array
数组中是所有 MapView 所显示的 Annotation
of annotations, that's all the annotations that the map view is showing,
不过这是一个只读属性
but that's read only properties,
你不能那样设置数组
so you can't set the array that way,
你需要使用 addAnnotation 方法
you have to use these add annotation methods
或是 addAnnotations 删除也是一样
or add annotations, and same thing removing them.
添加和删除需要用到这些方法
So you add and remove them with these methods,
你不能直接对数组进行操作
you don't manipulate that array directly.
这其实是一个很好的主意
It's a pretty good idea, if you can,
如果你有信息
if you have the information,
你可以预先把所有 Annotation 加到 MapView
to add all of your annotations up front to the map view.
实际上 添加 Annotation 开销很小
Adding an annotation is actually pretty low overhead,
特别是 Annotation 目前不在屏幕上的情况下
especially if that annotation is not on screen currently.
这是因为这些 MKAnnotationView
And that's because those MK annotation views,
这些带有对话框的大头针
the little pin that does the call out,
这些东西会像表格视图的行一样被再利用
those things are reused like a table views rows.
如果你有数百个 Annotation 但屏幕上只显示五个
So if you have hundreds of annotations, but only five of them are on the screen,
这时你就只需要创建五个 MKAnnotationView
you're only going to create 5 of those MK annotation views,
程序使用过程中 有些会从屏幕上消失
and as you kind of move around in the world and they go off-screen,
新的就可以再利用它们
they'll get reused for new ones.
预先把所有 Annotation 加到 MapView
So letting the map view all the annotations up front,
对于管理内部性能非常有帮助
it's nice to help it manage its internal performance, or whatever.
一般这是推荐的 不过你并不总知道
So it's generally recommended, but you don't always know,
有时 你并不能预先知道所有 Annotation
sometimes you don't know all the annotations up front,
它可能是实时发生的
it's happening in real time or something.
Annotation 是怎么样的呢
So, what do annotations look like?
一般是一个大头针
They generally look like a pin,
不过在 MKAnnotationView 中有很多方法可以调用
but there's a lot of methods that you can call in MK annotation view
你还可以创建 MKAnnotationView 的子类
and you can also subclass MK annotation view
画一个不同于大头针的东西
to draw something different in a pin, and this call
而这个对话框则较难创建子类让其变得不同
out is a little more difficult to subclass and make different.
如果只用这种有左右视图的对话框就够了
So if you can get by with just doing this left and right call out business,
那将很好 毕竟这会很简单
then that's good because that's easy.
如果你还想做更多 那将不属于这门课的范畴
If you want to do more, then it's kind of beyond the scope of this class
你需要自己去查怎么做
and you're going to have to do some searching around.
可以是可以 不过要在基本对话框的标题 副标题
It's doable, but doing something different than that basic call out with title, subtitle,
左右附属视图之外做别的 会比较困难
left and right accessory view is a little more difficult.
对话框的内容很有趣 什么时候设置这些呢
What, the contents of that call out are kind of interesting, when do you set those up?
MapView 有一个委托 我们会谈到
Well, there is a map, okay, the map view has a delegate we're going to talk about,
MapView 委托的一个方法就是
and one of the map view delegate methods is essentially
为我创建这个 MKAnnotationView
build this MK annotation view for me,
包括左右附属视图 把这些也 alloc init 了
including the left and right accessory views, you know, alloc init those, as well,
你可以在创建时加载这些
and you can load those up at the time you build it,
你也可以等到大头针被点时再加载这些
or you can wait until the pin is pressed to load those up.
为什么要等大头针被点时再加载 AnnotationView 呢
Now why would you want to wait till the pin is pressed to load up those annotation views?
看看这个例子
Well, let's look at this example right here.
你有一个缩略图
You've got that thumb nail.
如果缩略图需要 Flickr 取回
What if that thumb nail is, requires a Flickr fetch?
我们肯定不想对整个世界的所有大头针取回照片
Okay, well you don't want to fetch that photo for all the pins in the entire world,
仅仅对屏幕上可见的取回照片就够让人吃不消了
or even all of the pins that are visible on screen.
这时 你就只希望在大头针被点时再取回 Flickr 信息
You only want to load that Flickr, do that Flickr fetch, when a pin is clicked on.
MapView 中有一个委托方法
So there's this delegate method in the map view
叫 mapView didSelectAnnotationView
called map view did select annotation view,
点大头针时它会被调用
it'll get called when you click on a pin, that's a good place
这时再 Flickr 取回会更好
to like do that Flickr fetch.
加载对话框中的信息
Load up the callout.
我们会在 demo 中演示这是怎么做的
And we're going to do that in the demo and see how that works too.
我们有这些 MKAnnotationView
So, we have these MK annotation views
来显示这些 id
that are going to show these ID MK annotations,
两者如何关联起来呢
how do those two get connected up, and they get connected
这需要通过这个 MapView 委托方法
up by this map view delegate method
mapView viewForAnnotation
called map view, view for annotation,
它会返回一个 MKAnnotationView
and it returns a view for annotation.
这同表格视图中的 cellForRowAtIndexPath 几乎一样
This is almost exactly the same as cellForRowAtIndexPath in table view.
cellForRowAtIndexPath 你给它一个 section 和一个行
cellForRowAtIndexPath, you give it a section and a row,
它会返回一个 UITableViewCell
it gives you back a UI table view cell,
一个视图 来显示那个行
which is a view to display that row.
这里也一样
Same thing here.
它会给你一个 Annotation
It's going to give you an annotation,
你给它返回一个 MKAnnotationView
and you're going to give it back an MK annotation view
来绘制那个 Annotation
to draw that annotation.
MapView 还有这个机制
Now, map view even has this mechanism.
dequeueReusable…这个 同表格视图一样
The dequeue reusable thing, like table view has.
你可以说 sender 这里也就是 MapView
Right? So you can say sender, which is the map view there,
dequeueReusableAnnotationViewWithIdentifier
dequeue reusable annotation view with identifier,
给一个标识符
you give an identifier,
如果它在 MKAnnotationView 上有一个大头针视图
and if it's got a pin view on MK annotation view that it
被丢到屏幕上
got thrown off the screen
而且它能再利用它 它就会把它引入 并在这里给你
and it can reuse it, it'll bring it in, and give it to you here.
但是如果没有
But if it doesn't have any,
想想在表格视图下 会发生什么
then in the table view case, what happens?
系统会自动复制原型 对吧
We, the system will automatically duplicate that prototype, right?
故事板中我们设置有原型单元格
You got the prototype cell that we set up in the storyboard,
复制它 但这里不会这样
and you'll duplicate it, but that doesn't happen here,
因为地图视图中没有这个
because we don't get to do that in the map view,
地图视图没有原型单元格这些
the map view doesn't have all this mechanism for prototype cells and everything.
如果这个返回 nil dequeueReusable…这个
So, if that comes back as nil, the dequeueReusable thing,
我们就需要自己来 alloc init MKAnnotationView
then we have to alloc init the MK annotation view ourselves.
例如这里 我创建的是 MKPinAnnotationView
So here, for example, I'm making an MK pin annotation view,
在 iOS 中 这能绘制一个红色大头针
which comes in iOS, it's the thing that can draw a red pin,
应该也可以是紫色或是别的颜色 我可以 alloc init
I think you can do purple and one other color, and I just alloc init
使用 initWithAnnotation reuseIdentifier
with init with annotation, reuse identifier.
这里在 alloc init 时传入 reuseIdentifier
Now the fact that I passed that reuse identifier there when I alloc init,
意思是 如果它被丢出
it means that if it ever gets thrown out,
它就会回到再利用队列
it will come back in the reuse queue.
这就是将它同再利用队列关联起来的东西
So that's the thing that ties it to the reuse queue,
这些东西就是这样来回折腾的
so that's how things go back and forth.
然后这里面 我还要设置我的左右附属视图
And then, inside there, I might also set up my left and right accessory views,
或许不放内容
maybe not put the content in there,
例如图像 不过我要创建 UIImageView
like the image, but I might create the UI image view, right,
将这设为左侧的
and set that to be the left one
然后将按钮设为右侧的
and then set the button to be the right one.
在这之外 如果不是视图
Outside of that, if not a view, okay,
现在我有了一个视图 要么出列
so now I have a view either that I DQ'd
要么我自己创建
or that I made myself,
这里我加载了加载代价小的东西
here's where I load up whatever is cheap to load up.
到 MKAnnotationView 中
Into that MK annotation view.
这里不要做代价大的事
You wouldn't want to do expensive things here,
代价大的要等被点时再加载
we're going to wait till it's clicked.
如果这里是马上要显示的关于大头针的信息
If this, if it's something that's going to be displayed immediately about the pin,
例如你要用大头针以外的别的图像
like you're using a different image than the pin,
那这里显然就需要设置
then obviously you would need to set that here,
你不能等到点击时再加载这个
you can't wait till it's clicked on to load that up.
MKAnnotationView 有些什么属性
So what kind of properties are there on this MK annotation view,
从那个方法中返回的东西
the thing you're returning from that method?
显然有 annotation 有左右附属视图
There's obviously the annotation, there's the left and right call out accessory view,
这些都是你可以设置的 UIView
you see those are just UI views that you can set.
还有是否启用
There's whether it's enabled, there's even,
甚至还有是否可拖动
there's even whether it's dragable.
如果 MKPin 是可拖动的 那么 annotation
If the MK pin is dragable, then the annotation
就不仅需要实现坐标方法
has to not only implement that coordinate method,
它还需要实现设置坐标方法
it has to implement the set coordinate method.
因为你要把那个大头针拖着
Because you're going to pick that view up, pin up,
移动到别的地方 annotation 需要移动
and move it when it drops, the annotation has to be moved,
因此 这里需要有一个设置坐标的方法
so it has to have a set coordinate method.
否则可拖动属性就无法正常工作
Otherwise setting dragable here is not going to, to work.
然后这里还有一个 image 属性
And then the image that you see here, this property,
这是替代大头针的图像
that's the image that replaces the pin.
你不用大头针
That's instead of the pin.
这并不是对话框中的图像
That's not the image that's in the call out, that's,
并不是左附属对话框视图中的那个图像
we're going to put in the left accessory call out view, call out accessory view.
有一点很酷 如果你将
One thing that's kind of cool, if you set one
一个附属视图设置为 UIControl
of the accessory views to be a UI control,
最好的例子是 UIButton 继承自 UIControl
most notably a UI button, inherit from UI control, then,
那么你就可以将按钮放到对话框的附属视图中
yeah, you can put that button in the call out accessory view
你可以设置目标动作
and you can set up target action to it
这些都没问题 或许能够工作
and that would all be fine, that would probably work,
不过由于这在 MKAnnotationView 中非常常用
but since that's so common to do in a MK annotation view,
这里有一个很棒的地图视图委托方法叫 mapView
there's a nice map view delegate method here called map view
annotationView calloutAccessoryControlTapped
annotation view call out accessory control tapped
在用户轻击时 它会被调用
that will get called if the person taps on it.
如果你将按钮放到对话框中
So if you put a button in that little call out,
用户轻击它 这个就会被调用
and someone taps on it, this will get called,
你会知道哪个 AnnotationView 被点击了
and you will know which annotation view was tapped on,
你不需要对按钮进行目标动作操作
right, and you won't have to do target action in that button.
我在 demo 中也会演示这个
So we'll do that in the demo, as well.
再看 didSelectAnnotationView
So, did select annotation view.
这在地图视图委托中被调用
So this is the thing that gets called in the map view,
它叫 mapView
delegate map view, its called map view, colon,
didSelectAnnotationView 当大头针被点击时
deselect annotation view, when a pin is clicked on, okay,
当有人点击了红色大头针
when someone actually clicks on that red pin.
它会自动弹出对话框
Now, it's going to automatically put the call out up as long as
只要 MKAnnotationView 中设置了属性 canShowCallout
you set the property can show call out in the MK annotation view,
顺便说下 如果你在创建视图时
by the way, if you don't implement that annotation view,
不实现 mapView viewForAnnotation 委托方法
view for annotation delegate method where you build the view,
它会自动给你创建一个
it'll automatically create one for you,
就只有一个大头针 没有左右对话框附属视图
it's just going to be a pin, it's going to have no left and right call out accessory,
不过对话框中有标题和副标题
but it will show the call out with the title and subtitle.
这就是不设置时的情况
That's what you get if you don't do anything.
demo 中我也会演示这个
We'll do that in the demo too.
这里 在 didSelectAnnotationView 中
So, here in did select annotation view,
我点大头针 这里我可能就需要 Flickr 取回了
I clicked on the pin, here's where I might say oh, let's do that Flickr fetch.
至少在另一个线程中发起取回
You know, at least let's fire it off in another thread here.
我们甚至都不需要浪费时间去发起
We don't even want to waste our time firing it off,
但愿你们在作业中也学到了这个
and hopefully you're learning this in your homework too,
你不希望为不在屏幕上的行取回缩略图
you don't want to really fetch that thumb nail for a row that's not on screen,
这样做是浪费时间
it's kind of a waste of time to do that.
这里也一样
Same thing here.
在有人点大头针之前
Until someone clicks on that pin,
我们不希望发起 Flickr 取回
we probably don't want to fire this Flickr fetch off.
Flickr 取回以后 就像表格视图一样
When the Flickr fetch comes back, just like the table view,
我们需要小心地确保
we're going to have to be careful to make sure
这个对话框还同这个 annotation 保持着关联
that this call out is still associated with this annotation
因为这些东西会被再利用
and all that because these things get reused,
同表格视图中行会被再利用一样
just like the table view rows get reused.
无论如何 这里你可以加载对话框附属视图
But anyway, so this is where you could load up your call out accessory views.
这里你或许还可以 segue
You could also maybe segue here. This might be a place to segue,
不过 segue 需要在代码中进行 因为你没办法
but you would have to segue in code here, and, because there's no way
在故事板中从大头针进行 control 拖动
in storyboard to like control drag from the pins,
它们不在屏幕上 直到你开始添加 annotation
they're not on screen, until you start adding annotations,
因此这里我们需要手动 segue 我会在 demo 中演示
so here we could manual segue and we'll do that in the demo.
你可以配置地图显示的方式
You could configure the way the map displays.
首先 地图的显示就像是地图 app
Okay, first of all, the map's display is just like the maps app.
我不打算细讲所有地图配置方面的细节
So I'm not really going to go into all the things you can configure about the map,
不过任何你能在地图 app 中做的事
but pretty much anything you can do in the maps app,
包括 3D 旋转 缩放
including the 3D and rotating around, and zooming in and out,
都能在地图视图中做到
all of that you can do with the map view.
还包括混合模式
Also including hybrid mode,
卫星图和道路图覆盖在一起 这些都可以做到
where it's a satellite image overlaid with roads and all that, that's all doable.
你显然需要查阅 MKMapView API
So you want to definitely check out the MK map view API
看你能做多少了不起的事情
to see all the incredible amount of things you can do.
你可以显示用户当前的位置
You can show the user's current location.
这会用到上次课我讲到的 Core Location 内容
So it'll go use that core location stuff we talked about in the last lecture,
使用 GPS 来知道用户当前在哪
find out where the user currently is using GPS,
它会在地图上显示这个
it'll show that on your map.
你还可以进行一些限制
You can also restrict things about it,
或许你不希望用户使用 3D 模式
maybe you don't want the user to go into 3D mode,
这时你可以关闭 pitchEnabled 属性
then you can turn the pitch-enabled off
这样它就会无法倾斜
and it won't be able to pitch.
倾斜可以通过两根手指的手势来做到
They pitch by doing kind of a little two-finger gesture there,
关闭后你就不能这样做了 旋转也是
they won't be able to do that if you turn this off, same thing with rotate,
也许你希望北一直往上 不希望用户旋转
maybe you'll always north up and you don't want them to be able to rotate around
你也可以这样做
to a different, then you can do that.
我简要讲讲地图的 3D
So let's talk briefly about the 3D of the maps,
这个 3D 有一个很大的问题 它并不是真正的 3D
and a big issue with this 3D, it's not really 3D,
而是一种 2.5D
it's kind of 2 and a half D, right?
这是一个 2D 地图 不过它有一些信息
This is a 2D map, but, you know, it has some information
关于建筑及其 3D 表示
about buildings and their 3D representations,
因此在倾斜时 你就可以看到一种 3D 表示
so kind of when you pitch up, it can show you a bit of a 3D representation.
代码中同这交互的主要方式是
The main way you're going to interact with that in code is you're going to want to
指定摄像头在哪
specify where the camera is.
摄像头从哪里看街道
Where is the camera that's looking at the streets,
或是地图上别的什么
or whatever, that the person looking at the map,
你可以指定摄像头 通过设定摄像头在哪
and you can specify the camera via it, where a coordinate or where the camera is,
它指向哪里
and which way it's pointing,
倾斜了多少 处于什么高度
and how much is pitch, and what altitude it's at,
不过最简单的做法是使用这个类方法
but one of the easiest ways to do it is using this class method here,
cameraLookingAtCenterCoordinate
camera looking at center coordinate
fromEyeCoordinate eyeAltitude
from eye coordinate, eye altitude.
眼睛坐标和眼睛高度 这是摄像头的位置
So, the eye coordinate and the eye altitude, that's where your camera is.
使用经纬度 确定摄像头在世界上的坐标
Where in the world, okay, using the coordinates, latitude and longitude,
还有就是摄像头在多少米的高度上
your camera is how, what is the altitude of your camera, in meters,
然后是你在看哪个点
and then what point are you looking at?
明白了吗 这样就能设置摄像头了
You see how that's a way to set your camera? So you can do that to set your camera,
设置摄像头有一点很酷
one thing that's really cool about setting your camera,
当你从一个地方移到另一个地方
when you move from one place to another, you can kind
你可以将摄像头往上移到空中 这个会动画显示
of move your camera up into space and it'll animate that,
然后往下到新地方
and then come back down in the new place
这就对用户进行了定位定向
and it really orients your user where they are on the planet
随着他们从一个位置到另一个位置
as they go from thing, from location to location.
有问题吗 没有
Question? No.
好 再看区域
Okay. What about the region,
考虑我们正在看地图的哪里
what about where on the map we're, we're seeing?
区域的设置要使用这个 MKMapView 属性 region
So the region is set with this property in MK map view called region.
这是一个 MKCoordinateRegion
It's an MK coordinate region,
MKCoordinateRegion 是中心坐标经纬度
an MK coordinate region is center-coordinate latitude and longitude,
和一个跨度
and then a span.
经纬度Δ 经度多少度
Latitude and longitude delta, how many degrees of longitude,
纬度多少度
how many degrees of latitude
这告诉了你 任何时刻地图上显示的是什么
that tells you what's showing in the map at any given time.
这是可写可读的 你可以设置地图给它
And this is writable and readable, so you can set the map
你也可以找到它现在在哪
to it and you can also find out where it is now
在用户采用捏拉或别的什么手势时
after the user is done pinching or whatever.
你还可以让地图维持它当前的缩放尺寸
You can also just have the map keep its current zoom
只通过设定中心坐标来移动
and just move around by setting the center coordinate.
这些你们应该都能预料到 这个地图类非常强大
This is all exactly what you would expect, is this map class is super powerful.
这是 iOS 中内容非常丰富的类之一
I mean, one of the more action-packed classes in all of iOS, which is what it can do.
还有很多 C 函数能够换算…
And there's a ton of C functions to convert between.
这只是一个视图 地图视图是一个 UIView
Okay, this is just a view, map view is a UI view,
显然你有经纬度计的地图坐标
and of course you've got map coordinates in latitude and longitude,
你还有 x 和 y 计的视图坐标
and then you've got view coordinates in X and Y.
有时 你希望在两者之间进行换算
So sometimes you want to convert between those two,
因此 它有很多 C 函数来做这个
so it's got a bunch of C functions for doing that
还有很多方法 这样你就能弄清
and a bunch of methods, as well, so that you can kind of find
发生了什么 他们在触碰哪里
out what's going on, where they're touching,
什么导致了事情的发生 等等
what's causing things, etc.
这在地图视图中有很多
So there's a lot, a lot in the map view there.
这个地图视图委托方法…
This map view delegate method,
地图视图委托方法有大约 20 个
there's about 20 map view delegate methods,
我只能讲到其中很少几个
I can only cover a tiny few here,
像 viewForAnnotation 和 didSelectAnnotationView
like view for annotation and did select annotation view,
不过还有一个很有趣 也就是 didChangeRegion
but another interesting one is did change region.
说它有趣是因为 它会在
And the reason this is interesting, this gets called,
地图发生动画 四处移动 变换摄像头时被调用
if the map is animating, moving around, changing the camera or something,
完成后 它会显示一个新区域
when it's done, it'll be showing a new region,
它会发送这个消息给你
it'll send this message to you.
这有什么重要的呢
Why is that important?
为什么你要这样
Why would you want that?
因为如果你想有动画
Well, because if you're going to do animation,
例如现在显示的是旧金山 而用户想要看到纽约
like I'm showing San Francisco and the user now wants to see New York,
如果你只是设定纽约的坐标
if you just say set the coordinate New York,
它会呼地一下跳到纽约
it's going to go whoosh, over to New York,
整个国家会在半秒之内瞬间被掠过
and the whole country is going to rip by in about half a second.
这就没有任何动画 但是如果你想
So it's not going to be much of an animation, but if you want
将摄像头往上移到美国上方几千米的高空
to move your camera up over the United States a few thousand meters,
然后再回到下面
and then go back down.
你就需要知道你到上面以后
You'll need to know when you get up to the top
动画又会开始往下
so that you can start the animation going down, and so,
到上面时 区域动画会被调用
region to animated will get called when you get to the top,
动画会将摄像头移到上面去
you start the animation to move the camera to the top,
到上面 区域被设置
when it gets to the top and the region is set,
它会调用这个 区域将是整个美国
it'll call you this, and the region will be the whole United States,
然后动画就可以开始回到下面
and then you can start your animation and go back down.
优秀的 app 应该首先上升
And really, for nice apps, you might go up,
下降到纽约 然后沿街道移动
down to New York, and then drive down the street.
这是一个很酷的动画
It's kind of really cool animation,
每一步 你都希望使用这个转到下一步
that each of those steps, you want to use this to go to the next step,
而不是用动画的完成处理器
not the completion handlers of the animation things,
这个更好 因为这里会有各种东西
this is much better, because this is going to have all,
它会进行旋转等等
it's going to do all the rotation, when everything settled down,
将一切安排妥帖
it's almost like the settle down,
几乎就像是动态动画器中的 didPause
the did pause we had in the dynamic animator.
这对于好的地图动画是非常重要的方法
So that's an important method to know if you're going to do good map animation.
除了地图视图之外 我们还有搜索
Alright, so in addition to the map view, we also have searching.
局部搜索同 GeoCoder 很像 但强大很多
So local search, kind of like a geo coder, but lots more powerful.
这能让你的用户指定
This basically lets you have, specify,
一个自然语言查询
let's your user specify a natural language query,
例如这里我可以创建一个搜索 Ike's 的请求
like here I might create a search request for'Ikes'.
我可以在斯坦福校园的区域内进行搜索
And I might search in a region which is Stanford Campus,
然后我发送这个 当然 这个会经过网络
and then I fire this off, of course, this is going to go over the network,
并非所有信息都在设备上
not all this information is on your device.
它会经过网络
It's going to go over the network,
它会取回 会找到结果
it's going to do a fetch, going to figure this out,
它会返回给你
and it's going to return to you
并调用这个完成处理器
and call you to this completion handler
你说 startWithCompletionHandler
so you do it with start, with completion,
它之后就会调用完成处理器
it'll call the completion handler later,
你会得到一个由 MKMapItem 组成的数组
and you're going to get an array of MK map items.
MKMapItem 也就是描述地图上位置的项目
MK map items are basically things that describe a place on the map.
其中包含有 MKPlacemark
And they have inside of them an MK place mark,
这是关于地图上位置的细节信息
which is detail about a place on the map,
例如邮编 或是所处区域 诸如此类
like the postal code or region it's in, things like that.
MKMapItem 很酷 因为这里有一个方法
MK map item is kind of cool because it, there's a method
叫作 openInMapsWithLaunchOptions
in there called open in map with launch options,
把这发送给一个 MKMapItem
and if you send that to an MK map item, it will
它会离开你的 app 启动地图 app 并在那里显示
leave your app, launch the maps app and show it there.
就算你不想有一个地图视图以及所有这些
So if you don't want to have a map view and all that stuff,
你还是可以使用这个局部搜索
you can still use this local search and then switch
然后切换到地图 app 来显示特定位置
over to the maps app if you want to show them that particular location.
请讲
Yeah?
问题是 地图图块本身是怎样的
Yeah, so the question is what about the tiles of the map itself?
所有地图数据
All that map data?
这些显然也不在你的手机上 也需要下载
Yeah, that's clearly not on your phone as well, that's downloaded too.
最开始看地图上的位置时 它将是一个网格
So when you first look at a place on the map, it's just going to be like a grid,
就像是星际迷航中的空甲板
kind of like the hollow deck in Star Trek or whatever,
只是一个网格 然后再填入图块
like just a grid, and then it's going to fill in with the tiles.
下载有多快取决于你的网络有多快
And depending how fast your network is, that's how fast it's going to download it.
这些都会发生在后台 你甚至不知道
So yeah, that's all happening, though, in the background, you don't even know.
You have no idea what's going on.
你可以找到委托方法
You can find out there are delegate methods
说获取这个图块 如果你想知道 它会告诉你
that said got this tile, you know, it'll tell you if you want
但一般情况下你并不关心
to know, but generally you don't care.
还有办法能够获取从一个地方到另一个的方向
There's also a way to get directions from one place to another.
你只需要创建这个 MKDirection
So, you just create this MK directions thing,
你一开始要指定一个 MKMapItem 到最后
you're going to specify an MK map item at the beginning, at the end,
它会异步地经过网络
and it's going to, again, go asynchronously over the network
给你返回一个可选路径的列表
and give you back a list of possible routes that you can take,
这些返回的路径将有文字描述
and these routes are going to come back with text descriptions, you know,
例如高速公路 101 走这么多 等等
take highway 101 for this much, or whatever,
此外 它们还会返回 MKPolyline
and also they're going to come back with the MK polylines.
MKPolyline 顾名思义 也就是一些直线
An MK polyline, exactly what you would think, it's a bunch of lines,
一条多段线 例如图中的蓝线
and this polyline, you can see the blue line here,
或是紫线
or the purple lines,
也就是如何对从地图上一处到另一处的描述
is basically a description of how to draw and go from place to place in the map,
这非常酷
which is really, really cool.
这绕过了一个问题 也就是 如果我有一条多段线
But it does beg the question if I got a polyline, in hand, how do I
那该如何画到地图上呢
put it on the map? How do I draw it on the map?
答案是 我们使用 overlay(覆盖图) 来画在地图上
And the answer is we draw on the map using overlays.
overlay 也就是
So overlays are
一些你想画在地图上的形状
essentially descriptions of some shape that you want to draw on the map.
多段线是一种 不过这里也可以是圆形
So a polyline would be one, but you could also do circles,
任意多边形 等等
you know, arbitrary polygons, things like that,
做法是 你创建这个形状
and the way this mechanism works is you create this shape,
例如一条 MKPolyline 你添加一个 overlay
like an MK polyline, you add an overlay,
使用 addOverlay 这里的 level 是说
you see that add overlay, the level there is whether it's
是高于道路 还是高于标签
above the roads or just above the, or above the labels,
在地图上的一切之上
which is kind of on top of everything in the map,
你可以让多段线高于道路
so you could have the polyline be on the roads
让 280 这些符号都在它之上 这会看起来很棒
and have things like 280 symbol be above it, which looks really cool.
之后 MKMapView 还会问你
But then, the MK map view is going to ask you later, okay,
要一个渲染器 来把这个画在地图上
now I need a renderer to draw this thing on the map.
MKOverlayRenderer
An MK overlay renderer,
有点像 MKAnnotationView
which is a little bit like that MK annotation view,
只是 MKOverlayRenderer 并非视图
except for an MK overlay renderer is not a view,
它是一个在地图上绘制的机制
it's more of a mechanism for drawing on the map,
然后这个渲染器就会被用于渲染地图
and then that renderer will be used to render on the map.
这些渲染器来自于 iOS 种类有很多
Now, these renderers come with iOS, there's a whole bunch of them,
圆形渲染器 多段线渲染器 多边形 还有图块渲染器
circle renderer, polyline renderer, polygon, there's a tile renderer.
图块渲染器很酷 因为它只渲染位图
The tile renderer is cool because it just renders bit maps, okay,
你还可以用它来替换来自苹果的数据
and you can actually use it to replace the data,
instead of the data, that comes from Apple.
如果你有自定义的地图 你可以有这个图块
So if you had your own custom map, you could have this tile
这有些复杂 因为你需要
and it's a little bit involved, because you're talking
能够放大缩小 它需要这个的 API
about being able to zoom in and out and it has an API for that,
不过你确实可以替换
but you could possibly replace, or you might just want
或许你想要世界上特定地方的图块
to tile some image over a certain place in the world.
所有这些都是内建的
And so all that stuff is built
都在 MKShape 和 MKOverlay 中
in with this MK shape stuff in, in MK overlay.
overlay 非常酷 你可以用它们做很多事
So, overlays are really pretty cool and you can do a lot
因此 我建议你们去看看它们
of stuff with them, so I encourage you to kind of look at that.
好 以上是关于地图
Okay. So that's it for maps.
这方面我会有一个大 demo
And I'm going to do a big demo of all this stuff
你可以看到这些的实际操作 不过演示前
so you can see all this stuff in action, but before I do that,
我还要讲另外一点会出现在 demo 中的内容
there's another thing I'm going to do in the demo that I want to talk about briefly,
也就是 embed segue
which is embed segues.
segue 方面 现在你们知道如何使用 push segue
So, so far about segues, you know how to do push segues,
这是在导航控制器中
when you're in navigation controller, you know how
拆分视图中你们知道如何使用 replace segue
to do replace segues in a split view, although
只是我没有演示
we didn't demo that and it's pretty rare
实际替换 detail 或 master 也很罕见
to actually replace the detail or the master.
segue 中 我们通常会把 detail 留在那里
In a segue, we usually just leave the detail there
然后一直去找它 Photomania 中就是这样做的
and go look for it all the time, like we did in photo mania.
popover segue 这是上次我们看到的
Pop over segues, we saw that last time, okay,
那里我们使用了弹窗
where we said we'll do a pop over.
这次我要讲的是 embed segue
And here's another one called embed segues.
embed segue 很酷
And an embed segue is really cool,
你创建一个 UIView
you create a UI view
在某个视图控制器的视图层级内
inside the view hierarchy of some view controller,
在这个 UIView 之内
and inside that UI view,
是另一个视图控制器的 self.view
is the self dot view of another view controller.
你将另一个视图控制器的 self.view
So you basically take another view controller's self
作为 UIView 嵌入到了另一个里面
dot view and embed it as a UI view inside another one.
这让你能够创建非常复杂的视图
So, that allows you to build pretty complex views
同时仍能将矩形区域的职责划分到 MVC 中
and still divide up the responsibility for a rectangular area into MVCs.
我会在 demo 演示
And I'm going to do this in the demo
到时你们会明白我这里讲的是什么
so you get a little better idea of what I'm talking about here.
Xcode 让这个非常非常容易做到
Xcode makes is really, really easy to do this.
你只需要到对象面板
You just go to the object palette and you're going
在下面找到所谓的 Container View(容器视图)
to find something down there called container view,
你将 Container View 拖到你想要的视图中
you drag that container view into the view you want
然后就会自动创建一个视图控制器
and then it's going to actually automatically create a little
带有一个到它的 segue
view controller with a segue to it,
不过你可以 control 拖动 从这个容器
but you can control, drag from this container
到任何你想嵌入的 VC
to any VC you want to be embedded there.
control 拖动后 它和其它 segue 没是区别
And then once you add control, drag, it's just like any other segue.
它是一个 segue 需要准备
It's just a segue. It has to be prepared, right?
因为它在这里需要显示一些东西
Because it's going to be displaying something in there, presumably.
其它方面 它完全一样
But otherwise, it's exactly the same.
不仅这个 segue 同其它 segue 很相似
And not only is that segue exactly like any other segue,
那个容器视图也和其它 UIView 很相似
the view, that container you see right there, that's just like any other UI view.
在主视图控制器中
So, in the host view controller,
如果你想隐藏 你可以设置它的.hidden
you can set its dot hidden if you want to hide it.
你可以改变它的 frame
You can change its frame, okay,
你可以动画展示它的 frame 变化和移动
you can animate its frame changing, moving around.
你可以做任何你想做的事
You can do anything you want,
这对你只是一个不透明的 UIView
it's just kind of an opaque UI view to you,
它是视图层级的一部分
it's part of your view hierarchy, you can take it
你将它从中抽出 放回里面
out of the view hierarchy, put it back in, okay,
只是它的内容会被绘制为
it's just that its contents are going to be drawn
其它某个视图控制器的 self.view
as the self dot view of some other view controller.
时机 这个需要小心
The timing this is little bit thing to be careful
这是进行设置的时机
of is the timing of setting things,
想想 这个嵌入发生在什么时候
because when does this embed happen.
它的 prepareForSegue 发生在什么时候
When does it's prepare for segue happen, basically?
相对于它嵌入到的视图控制器中发生的其它事情
Relative to other things happening in that view controller that it's embedded in,
例如 其 outlet 被设置等等
like that things outlets being set, etc.
答案是 这发生得很早
And the answer is it happens pretty early.
在 outlet 设置之前 就像其它 prepareForSegue 一样
Before outlet setting, just like all prepare for segues do.
很多时候
So a lot of times you're going to have
你需要在准备和 outlet 设置中写相同的代码
to do whatever code you do in the prepare also in your outlet setting,
如果它们相互依赖的话
if they depend on each other.
之前在 Photomania 中我们见过这个
And we've already seen this in photo mania before,
如果 prepareForSegue 依赖于一个 outlet
anything you do in your prepare for segue that depends on an outlet,
你就需要在 prepareForSegue 中这样写
you're going to do it in prepare segue,
同时在 outlet 设置器中也这样写
you might also do it in the outlet setter.
这样一个发生时 另一个就会实际工作
So whichever one happens second will do the actual work.
大家都理解了我说的吗
Does everyone understand what I mean by that?
没有 还是理解了
No? Yes?
谁理解了我说的是什么意思
Who does understand what I mean by that?
没有人 好
Nobody. Okay, well.
不看演示可能有点难于理解
Okay, it's maybe a little hard to conceptualize without seeing it,
demo 中我会讲到这个 但愿到时大家就懂了
so in the demo I'll talk about it again and hopefully it'll make sense.
好 让我们来做这个 demo
Alright, so let's do this demo.
这个 demo 很大
This is a very big demo.
我应该有时间把它做完
I think I have enough time to do it all.
讲稿在这里 确保我没忘记什么
Notes here, make sure, in case I forget something.
我们打算做什么呢
Okay. So what are we going to do?
我们将从之前做到的地方开始考虑 Photomania
We are going to start with photo mania where we left off,
这是之前我们已有的 Photomania
so here's the exact photo mania we had before.
这次 我们打算在 iPhone 故事板中工作
Where we left off. This time we're going to work in this iPhone,
然后复制到 iPad 故事板
in the iPhone storyboard and then we'll copy it over to the iPad storyboard,
我们可以说是在两者之间来回切换
so we're kind of going back and forth working on each one.
今天我们打算考虑 iPhone 版
Today we're going to go work on the iPhone one.
怎么做呢
So, what are we going to do here?
但愿你们认识这个
So this, hopefully you recognize this.
这是我们的故事板 这里有一系列拍照者
Right? This is our storyboard, this is a bunch of photographers.
点击一个拍照者 我们得到该拍照者
We click on a photographer, we get all the photos
拍的所有照片 现在是在一个表格中
by that photographer currently in a table.
这里我要创建的 UI 几乎完全相同
So what I'm going to build is same UI here, almost exactly,
只是这里不再是照片的表格
except for that instead of a table of the photos,
而是照片的地图
I'm going to put a map of the photos up.
对于拍照者的每张照片将有一个大头针
With a pin for every photo by that photographer.
我需要一个 PhotosByPhotographer 地图视图控制器
So I'm going to need a photos by photographer map view controller,
而不是一个 PhotosByPhotographer
instead of a photos by photographer
Core Data 表格视图控制器
core data table view controller.
这些还是需要从 Core Data 中取出
Okay, I'm still going to pull all of this out of core data and everything,
不过我们将不使用表格视图
but we're not going to be doing a table view.
我要做什么能理解吗
Does that make sense? What I'm going to do?
好 我们下面来拖动创建那个视图控制器
Alright, so let's go ahead and drag, create that view controller.
地图视图控制器也是视图控制器
So a map view controller is just a view controller,
我将拖出一个视图控制器
so I'm drag out a view controller here.
放在这下面 因为它将替换上面这个
We'll put it under here because it's going to be replacing this guy right here,
也就是表格视图控制器
which is the table view controller of it.
同任何视图控制器一样 这需要一个类
Now, as with any view controller, I need a class
现在这是 UIViewController
for this, right now it's, you know, UI view controller,
我需要一个自定义子类 让我来创建一个
so I need a custom subclass, let's go create that.
这个自定义子类将是一个常规的 UIViewController
And that custom subclass is going to be a regular, old UI view controller.
UIViewController
UI view, view controller,
和前面一致 我打算称其为
and I'm going to call it, to be consistent,
PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
photos by photographer map view controller.
名字显得有点长
They're getting to be pretty long names here, but,
我也可以称它为 MapMVC 不过这会有些奇怪
I could call it map MVC, but that's kind of weird.
这里就写 MapViewController 吧
So we'll call it map view controller, alright?
PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
So photos by photographer map view controller, we'll put it
和其它控制器放到一起 这里
where we put everything, we'll put it in with our controllers, right there.
我们得到这个
We got that.
在故事板中 让我们把这个设为地图视图控制器
In our storyboard, let's go ahead and set this thing to be a map view controller.
这里 PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
Here it is, photos by photographer map view controller.
让我们为这个创建 UI
Let's build a UI for this thing.
在这之前
Actually, before we do that,
我总喜欢为新类写公共 API
I always like to do my public API for any new class.
这个类的公共 API 同 PhotosByPhotographer
The public API for this class is exactly the same as the public API
Core Data 表格视图控制器的公共 API 相同
for the photos by photographer core data table view controller.
这里我们其实只是复制粘贴
In fact, we just copy and paste it here to this thing.
当然 这里我们需要导入
And of course we need to be import here.
和原来一样
So it's the same thing.
你在地图视图控制器中设置这个拍照者
You set this photographer in our map view controller,
这里拍照者的照片不再显示在表格中
and instead of showing the photos by that photographer
而会显示在地图视图中
in a table, it's going to put them in a map view.
回到我们的故事板 创建这个的 UI
So let's go back to our storyboard and build the UI for this thing.
这里腾出更多空间
And so, let's make a lot more space here.
像这样
And go like this.
把辅助编辑器弄出来
Get our assistant editor up here.
进入自动模式
Let's go to automatic mode.
到这里
Go here.
这是 PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController 的代码
So, here is the code for our map photos by photographer map view controller,
这些都不需要
we don't need any of this business.
删除掉
Clear that out.
我们需要一个地图视图
We're going to need a map view, so let's go ahead
下面抓取地图视图 它和文本视图这些很像
and grab a map view, that is just a view like text view
这里 这是地图视图
or any other view, here it is right here, map view.
拖出来放到这里
So I'm going to drag that out, put this in here.
这里我要考虑约束 点重置到建议约束
Maybe I want to do its constraints, so reset to suggested constraints.
看看这些
Let's go take a look at those
确保这里都很合理
and make sure it did something sensible.
看起来很合理 它会匹配大小
Oh. Yep, looks very sensible, so it's going to stick to the size,
无论 self.view 的大小是多少 它都会紧随它
so whatever size our self dot view is it's going to stick to it.
我们再为这个地图视图创建一个 outlet
Let's create an outlet for this map view.
control 拖动 起名为 mapView
So I'm just control, dragging, I'll call it map view.
这里于是得到了一个 outlet
Alright? So we got an outlet there.
注意到这里有错误和警告
Notice that we have this error and warning here.
问题在哪
What's the problem?
问题在于 我们需要导入 MKMapView
The problem is we have to import MK map view.
让我们这样做
So let's do that.
import
Import map kit slash map kit.
我说过 MapKit 的导入和之前我们做的不一样
Now, I told you that map kit, it's not enough just to import map kit like you did
不能只是导入 MapKit
for everything else we've done so far.
我们需要到上面这里进行项目设置
We have to go to our project settings, over here, at the top,
在上面的项目设置中
and in our project settings, along the top, you're going
你会看到这里的创建阶段
to see this thing here called build phases.
创建阶段指定了我们要关联的框架
And the build phases specifies what frameworks we link with.
关联二进制文件和库
Link binary with libraries.
不要忘记这一部分 否则在运行 app 时
So don't forget this part or when you run your app it's going
它会说 没有这个类 MKMapView
to say oh, no such class, MK map view.
我们点加号
Alright? So we're just going to hit plus.
你会看到
Now when you do that you're going to see
iOS7 有很多库和框架可供选择
that iOS 7 has a lot of libraries and frameworks that you can pick from here.
幸运的是 它支持搜索
And luckily it lets you search them,
我键入 map 这就得到了 MapKit
so I'm just going to type map, and here I get map kit.
这就包含了 MapKit 将它关联到我的应用
So now I've included map kit, I'm linking it in with my application so
这就行了
it'll work.
我们有了这个地图视图
Alright, so we've got this map view.
这之后我就立刻需要将我自己设置为
One thing I want to do right off the bat is set myself
这个地图视图的委托
to be this map view's delegate.
因为我要使用所有这些地图视图委托方法
Because I'm going to use all those map view delegate methods
我在幻灯片中讲过
we talked about in the slides.
这里我有这个
So, I have this here.
这是地图视图的 setter
So this is the setter for map view
我这里键入 _mapView = mapView
and I'm just hitting underbar map view is map view,
然后这里将地图视图委托设为 self
and here I'm setting the map views delegate to be myself,
这里它在警告我
of course it's warning me, because I have
因为我需要实现 MKMapViewDelegate 下面就来做这个
to implement MK map view delegate, so I will do that.
MKMapViewDelegate
MK map view delegate,
现在 警告没有了
and now the warning goes away
因为 MKMapViewDelegate 协议中没有必需方法
because there are no required methods in the MK map view delegate protocol.
所有方法都是可选的
All of them are optional.
这里我可能还要做一件事
Now, one other thing that I probably want
在我有一个设置模型的公共 API 时
to do here is what I always want to do when I have a
我总会做这件事
public API that kind of sets my model,
也就是键入如下这样的代码
which is to do things
self.title = 拍照者的名字 这会很好
like self dot title equals the photographer's name, okay, that's a nice thing.
而且这里 每次我设置拍照者时
And I also, here, every time I set that photographer,
我都需要重置 PhotosByPhotographer
I kind of need to reset the photos by photographer, right?
因为这里要做的就是显示拍照者的照片
Because the whole point here is that I show the photos
如果拍照者发生变化
by photographer, if you change the photographer,
照片也需要发生变化
I need to change those photos.
要做 PhotosByPhotographer 这些
So, to do the photos by photographer thing,
我需要创建一个新属性
I am going to create a new property.
名为 photosByPhotographer 加入这个
Called photos by photographer, so let's add that,
属性 非原子 强 这就是一个 NSArray
property, nonatomic strong, it's just going to be an NS array,
NSArray *photosByPhotographer
NS array, start photos by photographer.
这将是照片对象的
Okay, and this is going to be of photo objects.
这里再导入 Photo
So let's go ahead and import photo here too.
我们需要这个
We're going to need that.
这里是 photosByPhotographer 的 getter
Okay, and, here's the getter for photos by photographer.
很简单
Very, very simple, alright?
这是 getter 因此我只需要说
It's the getter, so I'm just saying if the photographer,
如果 photosByPhotographer 还没设置
photos by photographer is not set yet,
那我就将从数据库中取回它们
then I'm going to go fetch them from the database.
我于是创建一个取回请求 用于照片
So I create a fetch request, it's for photos.
我创建了一个谓词 whoTook = self.photographer
I create a predicate, who took equals self dot photographer,
而这里 在表格视图中
and here, we're in the table view,
我设置了取回结果控制器
I set the fetch results controller,
这里我打算在 context 中执行取回请求
here I'm actually going to execute the fetch request in the context.
这会返回一个数组 也就是这里我要存储的数组
And that returns an array, which is this array that I'm going to store right here,
然后我们返回它
and then we'll return it.
每次设置拍照者时
Now every time we set the photographer,
我都要将这个重置为 nil
I better reset this thing to nil.
当有人想要时 它会惰性地进行这个取回
It's going to lazily do this fetch whenever someone actually wants it,
但每次拍照者变化时 我需要将其设为 nil
but I better set it to nil every time the photographer changes,
否则它就不会进行这个惰性实例化
otherwise it's not going to do this lazy instantiation.
这个惰性实例化很棒 因为这是 Core Data 取回
This lazy instantiation is nice because this is core data fetch,
但它还在工作
but it's still work,
在有人想要这些 photosByPhotographer 机制之前
and I don't want to do this work until someone actually wants those photos by
我并不想要它在那工作
the photographer mechanism.
好 我们还需要做一件事
Alright. So the other thing we need to do is,
当地图视图被设置 或当模型被设置时
when our map view is set or when our model is set,
我们需要更新 annotation
we need to update the annotations.
地图上有很多 annotation
We've got all those annotations on the map
这将是 PhotosByPhotographer
that are going to be the photos by photographer,
我们需要更新这些
so we got to update those.
我们这里将有一个方法叫
So we're going to have a method here called update
updateMapViewAnnotations
map view annotations.
这里设置地图视图时需要调用它
And we're going to have call this both from here, when we set the map view,
这里设置模型时也需要调用它
and also from here, when we
因为我们不知道发生顺序是怎样的
set our model. Because we don't know what order this is going to happen.
我们不知道是模型在地图视图之前设置
We don't know if our model is set before our map view
还是地图视图在模型之前设置
or if our map view is set before our model.
无论哪种顺序
Either way, this
updateMapViewAnnotations 都需要做正确的事
update map view annotations better do the right thing.
这就是两处都要调用的原因
So that's why we're calling from both.
如何实现这个 updateMapViewAnnotations 呢
So, how are we going to implement this update map view annotations?
我其实讲过怎么做
Well, I told you what we're going to do,
我们要将照片对象设为 MKAnnotation
we're going to make a photo object be an MK annotation
因此我们在更新地图视图 annotation 时
so that all we need to do to update that map view annotations
只需要将照片加到地图
is add the photos to the map.
如何将照片转化为 id MKAnnotation 呢
So how are we going to turn photo into an id MK annotation?
答案是 我们需要做两件事
And the answer is two-fold. There's two things we need to do.
一是 我们需要修正我们的 Core Data 数据库
One thing, we need to fix our model, or our, you know, core data database,
来得到经纬度
to have the latitude and longitude,
显然 不知道照片在哪就无法显示在某个地方
otherwise, if we don't where the photo is, we obviously can't show it on there.
因此 我要添加纬度
Right? So, I'm going to add latitude,
很幸运 Flickr 会提供这个信息 经度
luckily Flickr provides this information, longitude,
在这里 我还可以添加缩略图 URL
and while I'm here I'm also going to add thumb nail URL,
等下我会讲 我们能用它做什么
and I'll show you what we can do with that in a moment too.
缩略图 URL 是一个字符串 本来应该是 URL
So a thumb nail URL is a string, it's actually a URL,
不过我们只能存储字符串
but strings the best we can do.
而经纬度都是双精度浮点数
Whereas the latitude and longitude are doubles. Double precision float point numbers.
我把这个加到我的数据库
So I'm just adding this to my database.
到上面这里
I'm going to go up here
为 Photomania 创建 ManagedObject 子类
and create my managed object subclasses for photo mania,
我只改变了照片 那么这里就只重新生成照片
I only change photo, so let's just only regenerate photo.
这个还是放到老地方
We'll put this, same place, as we usually do,
它问我想不想替换 我当然想
it's asking if I want to replace the other ones, of course I do,
现在 我的照片就有了经纬度
and now our photo has a latitude and longitude.
注意 这里是 NSNumber
Notice these are NS numbers here,
因为数据库中的一切都是对象
because everything in the database is an object.
当然 我们需要更新 Flickr 加载器
Of course we need to update Flickr's loader,
我们的 Photo+Flickr category
our photo plus Flickr category,
这是加载所有这些东西用的
right, which does the loading of all this stuff,
加载纬度 这里有个东西用于这个
to load up the latitude, here I have a thing for that,
这是纬度被加载 这里是经度
so here's the latitude being loaded up, here's the longitude.
它会到照片字典去找经纬度
It's just looking at the photo dictionary for the latitude and longitude.
我这里将双精度值转换为 NSNumber
I actually take the double value and then turn it into an NS number
以防这是一个字符串
just in case this is a string.
因为字符串也实现 doubleValue
Cause strings implement double value too,
或是将自身解释为双精度值 这里我要双保险
or that'll interpret themselves as a double value, so I'm just going to be double safe.
我不确定我能从 Flickr 得回什么
I'm not quite sure what I'm going to get back from Flickr,
不知道 JSON 中是字符串还是数字 这里是为了保险
whether it's a string or a number in the JSON, so I'm just being safe there.
然后这里的缩略图 URL
And then here at the thumb nail URL,
我抓取的是 FlickrPhotoFormatSquare
I'm just grabbing the Flickr photo format square,
你们在作业中处理缩略图时也是用的这个
which is what you're using for your thumb nail also in your homework.
现在 我们的数据模型已经加载
So now we've got our data model being loaded
这是来自 Flickr 的照片 信息已经够了
up with photos from Flickr that have enough information.
然后我们要将照片设为 MKAnnotation 要做这个
Now we need to make photo be an MK annotation, and to do that,
我需要加另外一个 category
I'm going to add another category.
我可以加入那个 Flickr category
I could put in that Flickr category,
但实现 MKAnnotation 的并不是一个 Flickr 的东西
but it's not really a Flickr thing that it implements MK annotation.
因此 我要创建一个新的 category 叫 Annotation
So I'm going to create a new category called the annotation category,
在照片上
on photo.
放到… 这仍然是模型的一部分
We'll put that, it's still part of our model.
这是 Annotation 的接口
Here's the annotation interface.
这个是空的
And, and this is, is empty.
这里我要做什么呢
So, what am I going to do here?
这里我要说 Photo 是一个 MKAnnotation
Actually, all I'm going to do is say photo is an MK annotation.
这里需要导入 MapKit
And I'll have to import MapKit here.
我说了 Photo 是一个 MKAnnotation
So I've said that photo is an annotation.
现在 我就能将照片放到照片视图中
Now I can put photos in that map view.
不过看这里的实现
But if I look at the implementation over here,
这里有一个警告
you're going to see that there's a warning.
这个警告是什么
What do you think this warning is?
没人知道吗
Nobody?
当然 请讲
Surely, yes?
对 缺少方法
Yes, missing methods.
因为我说了 这里
Because I said, here,
我实现了 MKAnnotation 协议
that I implement the MK annotation protocol,
但我没有实现坐标这些东西
but I don't implement that coordinate thing, so if I click
点这里 它告诉我 坐标属性需要定义
on this it says property coordinate has to be defined.
下面我们就来实现坐标
So let's implement coordinate here.
这很简单
It's really easy to do.
我们只需要返回一个 CLLocation 坐标
We just have to return a CL location coordinate.
我只需要获得经纬度双精度值就行了
I'm going to get it by just getting my latitude and longitude as double values.
这些是 NSNumber 这些是双精度
Remember, these are NS numbers, these are doubles.
这样警告就没了
So now I don't have that warning.
现在照片就是 id 了
Now a photo is an ID angle bracket MK annotation,
我于是可以把照片作为 MKAnnotation 放到地图视图中
and now I can just put a photo into a map view as an MK annotation.
下面我们来做这个
So let's go back and do that.
这是我的地图视图
There's my map view.
这是 updateMapViewAnnotations 方法
Here's the update map view annotations.
首先 我要删除所有已经存在的 annotation
First, I'm going to remove all of our existing annotations.
我要删除地图视图中已有的所有 annotation
Okay, so I'm just removing all the annotations that are currently in the map view,
然后 我要 addAnnotations
and then I'm going to add annotations
self.photosByPhotographer
self dot photos by photographer.
这些都是 Photo *
And I can, these are photo stars,
不过也是 id
but they're also ID angle bracket MK annotations.
因此这里我可以调用它们
So I can call them here.
查阅说明文档看 addAnnotations 你会看到
If we look at the documentation for add annotations, you'll see
它取的是一个 MKAnnotation 的数组 照片就是这个
it takes an array of MK annotations, and a photo is that.
我还要做一个很酷的事 我要放大地图
I'm going to do another cool thing, which is I'm going to zoom the map in
显示这个拍照者的所有照片
to show all the photos by this photographer.
我将以一种动画的方式来做这个
Now I'm doing this in an animated way, but that just,
不过这并不是缩小然后放大回去
that's not really going to like zoom out and then zoom back
像我之前所说的 而是咻地转到要去的位置
in like I was talking about, it's not going to zoom on over to where it is,
这并不是很好的动画
so it's not great animation,
你们要做的东西应该比这更好
you're probably going to want to do something much better than this.
这就是我们需要做的
So that's really all we need to make this work.
有一点 我确定你们学过
One thing, which you've I'm sure learned,
也就是 我们改变了 Core Data 数据库模型
is that we've changed our core data base model,
这样一来 已经在设备或是模拟器上运行的 Photomania
so the photo mania that's already on my device or my simulator,
就需要被删除
I'm going to want to delete that.
因为现在它的数据库是不兼容的
Because its database is now incompatible.
没有经纬度和缩略图 URL 在其中
It doesn't have latitude and longitude and thumb nail URL in there.
我们运行一下这个
So let's go ahead and run this.
但愿网络情况良好 我们能够获得 Flickr 信息
Hopefully our network is working and we can get stuff from Flickr.
有了 我们得到了一些东西
There it is, we got some stuff.
我们希望这里 当我们点击时
And now, what we'd like to have happen here is we click
看到的不是表格视图 而是地图
and instead of a table view here, right, we'd like to see this map.
如何做到这个 segue 呢
So how do we do that segue?
这里我们有这个 iPhone 的东西
Alright, we have this iPhone thing here.
这个地图视图的东西准备好了
We've got this nice map view thing ready to go,
我们希望 segue 到它 这个到这里的 segue
we want to segue to it, so this segue that goes here,
我们希望它往下到这里
we want it to go down here.
很简单
Really easy to do.
我只需要把这些放到屏幕上 然后演示给你们
All we have to do is make sure it all fits on screen, so I can show it to you.
好了
Here we go.
我只需要通过 control 拖动
I'm just going to segue by control, dragging
从拍照者表格视图中这一行 segue 到下面新的这个
from this row in the photographer's table view, down to our new one.
这是 push 因为我们在导航控制器中
It's a push, because we're in the navigation controller,
注意到 上面这个 segue 没了
and notice it took away this segue because I can only segue
因为这一行只能 segue 到一个地方
from this row to one place,
现在 我 segue 到的是下面的地图视图
and now I'm segueing to our map view down here.
现在我们有了这个 segue
So now we have this segue.
那拍照者的 Core Data 表格视图控制器呢
Now what about photographers control, core data table view controller?
它需要适当地为 segue 做准备
It has to prepare for segue properly, right?
这里是 prepareForSegue
So here's where it's prepare for segue
对应 PhotosByPhotographer
with the photos by photographer
Core Data 表格视图控制器
core data table view controller, so,
这里我们要对地图视图控制做一样的事
we're going to do the same thing here with a map view controller.
这里代码几乎完全一样 只是这里我用
So here, this is almost exactly the same code, it's just that I'm doing photos
PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
by photographer map view controller
代替 PhotosByPhotographer
instead of photos by photographer
Core Data 表格视图控制器
core data table view controller.
我们有这些 需要导入
And we have these because we have to import,
导入 PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
so let's go and import our photos by photographer map view controller.
这就解决掉了所有警告 很好
Hopefully it gets rid of all our warnings, that's good.
现在我们有了这个 segue 再试一次
So now we have this segue, so let's try again.
但愿我们的新 segue 能够工作
And hopefully our new segue will work.
我们有拍照者 点击 我们得到地图上的大头针
We got the photographers, we click, we got pins on the map.
显示该拍照者的所有照片 点击一个大头针
Showing all those photos by that photographer, and if we click on a pin,
它会显示出标题和副标题
it's actually going to show us the title and subtitle.
这些都没有副标题
None of these have subtitles,
看看能否找到一个有副标题的
let's see if we can find somebody who has subtitle.
这里 这里有一个人 从苏格兰
There we go, there's one, this person gets around, from Scotland all the way
一直跑到了非洲海岸
down to somewhere off the coast of Africa there.
这很酷 不过我们不能做到下一步的 segue
So this is kind of cool, but we can't do our next step of our segue,
我们不能 segue 到照片显示
we can't segue to showing the photo, and also,
而且这里要是有个小的照片缩略图就好了
wouldn't it be cool if we had a little thumb nail of the photo in here?
让我们能够
So that we could kind of look
在这个人拍的多张照片中查找
around at the various photos taken by this guy
直到找到我们想要的
until we find the one we want,
然后我们点击这里
and then we'll click on something over here
segue 到完整的照片显示
to segue over to our showing the photo in its grand, all its grandeur.
让我们来做这个
So let's do that.
把这些附属视图加进来
Let's put these accessory views in.
回到我们的地图视图控制器
Let's go back here to our map view controller.
腾出空间
Some space.
这是我们现有的地图视图控制器
Alright, so there's our map view controller, what we've done so far.
现在我们要用地图视图委托方法 这是我们的第一个
And now we're going to do that map view delegate method, this is our first one.
这个会返回 MKAnnotationView
This is the one that returns an MK annotation view
给定一个特定的 annotation
given a certain annotation.
这个是 mapView viewForAnnotation
So this is called map view, view for annotation,
给定一个 annotation
it's going to give an annotation, that's going
也就是我们的一张照片
to be one of our photos
它会要求我们返回一个视图对应那个 annotation
and it's going to ask us to return a view for that annotation.
出于时间考虑 这里就直接这样做
I think for speed here I have something, yeah, let's do that.
这会完成幻灯片上我讲过的内容
Okay, so this is going to do what we saw on the slides
它会有一个再利用 ID
where it's going to have a reuse ID.
顺便说下 这个代码片段非常好
I like, this, by the way, is a good code snippet to have.
可以看到 这是完全通用的
You can see this is kind of completely generic
用于在地图视图中做到 viewForAnnotation
for doing a view for annotation in a map view.
我有时喜欢用类名作为再利用标识符
I like to use the name of my class sometimes as my reuse identifier,
这对于再利用有而言 具有很好的唯一性
that's pretty unique thing to do for reuse.
这是 dequeue
Here's the DQ.
如果 dequeue 无法工作 我需要 alloc init 这个东西
If the DQ doesn't work, I have to alloc init this thing,
我还是想显示对话框 我希望有一个大头针
I still wanted to show a call out, I want it to be a pin
然后这里我设置好视图 带有我需要设置的那些
and then here I'm setting up the view with anything I need to set
它会设置 annotation
up here, it's just setting the annotation.
这里面 就是我们设置左右附属视图的地方
So, inside here is where we want to set up the left and right accessory views.
我们来做这个
So, let's do that.
左边这个将是 UIImageView
So the left one is going to be UI image view.
这里我要创建一个图像视图
So I'm going to create an image view here.
UIImageView alloc init
UI image view alloc init.
这里 alloc init 将使用 initWithFrame
And I'm going to actually alloc init with frame
这是 iOS 中我很不喜欢的一个地方
and this is one of the places in iOS I really don't like.
没有 API 能够知道 对话框有多大
There is no way, no API, to find out how big is that call out?
而我需要知道对话框有多大
So I'd really like to know how big that call
这样我才能知道图像视图要多大才合适
out so I can make my image view be a good size to really fit there.
很不幸 这里你需要设置固定数字
So this is a place where you have to, unfortunately, put magic numbers.
我发现的固定数字
And the magic numbers I found
对于图像视图是 46 乘 46
that really work is an image view that is 46 by 46,
这就能很好地匹配到左侧对话框附属视图中
that seems to really fit nicely in that left call out accessory view, right there.
这是这里很不幸的一点
So that's kind of an unfortunate piece of this.
现在 我将把这设置为左侧对话框附属视图
So now I'm just going to set that as the left call out accessory view,
然后右边将是一个按钮 我只想要一个按钮
and then the right one is going to be a button, I just want to do a button,
这个的代码我也有了
so I think I have a code for that one, yeah,
信息披露按钮 也就是这段代码
the disclosure button, so that's this code right here.
我要创建一个 UIButton 使用 alloc init
So I'm just going to create a UI button, alloc init.
我要将它的背景图像
I'm going to set its background image
设为这里的这个信息披露图像
to be this disclosure image I have right here.
让我到下面这里的图像库中
So let me go down here to my image assets.
把这个拖进来 像这样
And let's drag this in, like that.
名为披露 我没有高清版的 不过没问题
Disclosure, I don't have a high-res version, but that's okay.
顺便说下 这并不是很好的图像解决方案
This is kind of, this is not a great solution, by the way, to do an image here,
因为我们需要尊重地图视图的着色风格
because really we want to respect the tint color of the map view
而这个箭头是蓝色的
and that arrow is blue.
这很糟糕
So that's bad.
更好的做法是绘制一个
It'd be much better to either draw it
就算要使用图像 你也应该来周五辅导课
or if we are going to use an image, you should come to Friday's section
理解如何使用 Core Image 改变图像颜色
and understand how to change the color of an image using core image.
这是本周五辅导课我们要讲的内容
That's what we're talking about in Friday's section this week.
一则小广告
Little plug for that.
无论如何 demo 中就用这个了
But anyway, for demo purposes I'll use this thing.
然后使用 sizeToFit 来调整按钮图像
Now I'm going to size to fit this button to fit that image that I just did,
然后我将它设为右对话框附属视图
and then I'm going to set it as the right call out accessory view right there.
有问题
Question?
你是说… 我不确定
You mean is the, the, you know, I'm not sure.
如果视图很大的话
I believe it will size if you make a big view in there,
它会变得更大 但看起来会很糟糕
it'll make it bigger, but it starts to not look very good,
因此你需要选择大小 让它保持相同大小
so you kind of want to pick sizes that make it stay the same size
由于标题和副标题
because of the title and subtitle.
对话框这整个
It's a little bit, the whole thing with the call out thing is a little bit,
你需要逐像素或是逐点调整 很不幸
kind of, you have to tweak it pixel by or point by point, unfortunately.
我们来看看 到目前为止 我们都做了些什么
So, let's go ahead and take a look at what we got so far.
现在 我们来看一张照片 点出对话框
Alright? So now if we look at a photo and we do the call out.
这里有了图像的空间
We have room for the image.
只是图像还没放进来 这里还有了按钮
We're not putting the image in there yet, and we have this little button,
现在点击 它还什么都做不了
which when we click on does nothing.
我们正在推进
So we're getting closer.
让我们把图像放进来 同时点这个以后 segue
So let's put this image in there, and let's make it so clicking on this segues.
那如何将图像放到这个图像视图中呢
Alright. So, how do we put this image into the image view?
这里我有一个方法 叫作… 叫什么来着
Well, I'm going to have a little method to do it here called, what did I call this?
updateLeftCalloutAccessory
Update left call accessory, yeah,
这是做这个的方法
so here's my method that does this.
看起来有很多代码 其实不然
This looks like maybe a lot of code, but it's actually not that much.
我做的大部分是内省
Mostly what I'm doing is introspection to find
弄清左对话框附属视图是不是图像视图
out if the left call out accessory view is, in fact, an image view.
因为我可能有多个大头针 使用不同的对话框
Because I might have multiple pins with different call outs.
有些可能会显示照片
Some of them might be showing photos,
但有些可能会显示别的
but some might be showing something else.
也许别的这些
And maybe those are something else
没有图像视图作为左对话框附属视图
they don't have an image view as a the left call out accessory view.
我这里既检查确保了左对话框是图像视图
Alright? So I'm both checking to make sure that my left call out is an image view,
我还检查确保了 annotation 是一张照片
I'm also checking to make sure my annotation is a photo,
而不是别的什么
right, and not something else.
毕竟地图上有别的 annotation 很正常
Because it's perfectly reasonable on a map to have annotations,
可能有些是照片 有些是别的
some of which are photos, some of which are something else.
例如拍照者的家乡或是别的什么
The hometown of the photographer or something like that.
这里大部分就是这种内省
So that's what mostly what this is it just is introspection of those things.
有了照片和图像视图之后
Once I have a photo and an image view,
我就只需要这个骇人的图像
then all I'm doing is this horrendous image
使用 imageWithData dataWithContentsOfURL
with image data, data with contents URL,
为什么说骇人呢
and why is it horrendous?
显然因为我阻塞了主队列
Of course because I'm blocking the main queue,
这是 demo 我需要做这个
but this is a demo so I get to do it,
你们在作业中不需要 但我需要
you don't get to do it in your homework, but I do.
这会阻塞主队列
So, this is going to block the main thread
前往 Flickr 进行取回
for a short amount while it goes out to Flickr to fetch it,
不过 你们懂的
but you get the idea.
这里加个警告 我保证以后我会过来修正的
I put the warning in, I'm sure I'll go back and fix it some other day, yeah, sure.
这是这个 我们来看看
Okay. So that's that. Let's go ahead and look at that.
好 现在 如果我点击一个大头针
Alright, so now if we click on something and we click
这里应该有一个图像
on a pin, hopefully we'll get an image,
似乎无法工作 为什么呢
maybe that guy didn't have, oh, that's not working, why is that not working?
哦 不 不是这个原因
Oh! I, no, that's not why.
哦 我明白了 因为我们没有调用这个
Okay, so, oh, I see why, because we never called this.
显然应当调用 这样才行
Okay, it'd be nice to call that. It would probably work better.
在这里调用它
So let's call that from here.
这是 viewForAnnotation
Okay, this is the view for annotation.
我从 viewForAnnotation 调用这个左对话框
So I'm calling this left call out here from view for annotation, right,
因为我要为 annotation 返回一个小视图
because I'm returning the little view for annotation,
这包含对话窗视图的创建
that includes building the call out view,
这样应该就行了 我猜
so that'll work a lot better, I'm going to guess.
到这里
Alright, so here we go here.
点击 看起来很棒
Click this up, nice, that looks pretty good, right?
点这每一个 都可以看到缩略图
So if we click on each one, we kind of get a little look at it
这能帮我们决定 我们要看哪个
and it kind of helps us decide which one we want to step on,
我们再点这个
press on, and we'll press on this one.
不过这样做有个问题
Now there's a problem with the way I've done this though.
找一个照片很多的人
Let's find somebody who has a lot of photos.
但愿有人拍了很多照片
Hopefully somebody has a lot of photos.
谁呢 看起来 15 或是 16 张已经很多了
Somebody, well, eh, looks like 15 photos is, or 16, alright.
选这个吧
So let's click on this guy.
点这个时 注意 耗时很长
When I click on this guy, look, it's taking a long time.
斯坦福的网还很快
And this is a fast Stanford network, so,
至少不慢 但它仍然阻塞了主线程
it's not too slow, but it still, it's blocking the main thread,
而且阻塞得还很多
but it's blocking the main thread a lot.
为什么呢
And why is that?
因为它在为所有这 16 张照片取回缩略图
That's because it's fetching the thumb nail image for all 16 of those photos.
预先一次性取回
All at once up front.
我们不希望这样做 我们只希望在点大头针时取回
So we do not want to do that, we only want to do this fetch when you click on the pin.
因此 这里我们要实现另一个地图视图委托方法
So we're going to implement another map view delegate
可以看到这里有多少委托方法
method, and you can see how many methods, delegate methods,
地图视图有很多
the map view has, quite a few.
我们要的是下面这个 didSelectAnnotationView
We want this one down here, did select annotation view.
这在大头针被点时会被调用
That's get called when the pin gets clicked on,
把 updateLeftCalloutAccessory 这个移到下面来
so I'm just going to move this update left call out accessory view down to here.
现在运行时 哪怕有 16 张照片的人
So now, when we run, even the 16 guy
也会立刻加载 因为这里没有取回操作
is going to instantly come up, because you're not doing any fetching,
但点这个时 会有少许延时
but when we click on this, little delay.
现在我不能看到全部这 16 个 它们都堆在一起
Now I can't see all 16 of things because they're all stacked up,
这个 UI 有点小问题
it's a little problem with our UI,
或许我们应该有办法能够点其它的
we probably want to have some way to click other things,
这里要换照片似乎不那么容易 无论如何
you can kind of click other things one, but, anyway.
下面 在点这里时 我希望看到这张照片
But now we want to, if I click here, I want to see this image
在图像视图控制器中 看到完整大小的
in my image view controller, full-size.
下面来实现这个
So now let's implement this little thing.
这里 我们需要另外一个地图视图委托方法
And that it's going to do, we're going to do with another map view delegate method.
这个我讲过
This is the one I told you about,
calloutAccessoryTouched 上面这个 看到了吗
the call out accessory touched, it's the one up here, see it?
calloutAccessoryControlTapped
Call out accessory control tapped.
这个在任何左 / 右附属视图中的
So this gets called whenever any left or right accessory view,
UIControl 例如 UIButton 被点时 会被调用
that is a UI control, like UI button is, gets tapped. This gets called.
现在我只有一个 因为图像视图并不是 UIControl
Now I only have one because the image view is not a UI control,
这个我不需要担心
so I don't have to worry about that.
这里面 我可以 segue
So inside here, I can segue.
但如何 segue 呢
But now, how do I segue.
我从未演示过如何做这个 我在幻灯片中讲过
I've never shown you how to do this, we did cover it in the slides,
但我从未演示过 如何从这里 segue
but I never showed you, how do I actually segue from here?
回到我的故事板
Because if I go back to my storyboard,
没有能够 control 拖动的大头针
there's no pins for me to control, drag from?
怎么办呢
How do I, what am I going to do?
这里我们只需要从代码中进行 segue
So what we're going to do here is segue from code,
做法是这样的
and here's how you segue from code.
control 拖动 从这个视图控制器
You control, drag from the from view controller
到要到的视图控制器 从整个视图控制器
to the to-view controller, just from the whole view controller,
而不是从任何按钮或是别的什么
not from any button in here or anything like that,
如果这里你有很多按钮
and if you had a lot of buttons in here,
你可以从这个栏 control 拖动
you could control, drag from this bar
这样你就不会意外地从一个按钮 control 拖动
so you don't accidentally control, drag from a button.
我这里不是从地图视图进行 control 拖动的
So I'm just going, and I'm not control, dragging from the map view here.
这里我将从下面这里 control 拖动
In fact, here I'm going to control, drag from down here.
这是我的 PhotosByPhotographer
So here's my photos by photographer, here's the,
这是表示控制器本身的图标
the icon that represents the controller itself, so I'm going
我从这里 control 拖动到这个
to control drag from here up to this guy.
相信我
Oh well, trust me.
从这里 control 拖动到这里
I'm going to control drag from here to here.
好了
There we go.
不 这个到这里
No. This to here.
抱歉 好了
Sorry. There we go.
我从这个视图控制器 control 拖动到这个
Alright. So I'm going to control, drag from this view controller to this one.
我从这个视图控制器创建了一个 segue
So, I'm creating a segue here from that view controller
到另一个
to the other one,
很通用 从一个控制器到另一个控制器
generically, from the controller to the other controller,
很重要的是 我需要给它取个名字
and it's very important here I have to give it a name.
我将它称作 Show Photo
So I'm going to call it show photo,
这就是它的作用 显示这张照片
because that's what it does, it shows this photo.
为什么要取名呢
Why do I need to give it a name?
因为在代码中 我需要引用这个 segue
Because from code, I have to refer to this segue,
引用需要用到名字
and I'm going to refer to it by name.
叫 Show Photo
We'll call it show photo.
我们回头做这个 只需一行代码
So let's go back and do that. This is a one-liner.
我只需要说 self…
I just say self,
我要调用 UIViewController 中的这个方法
and I'm going to call this method in UI view controller,
performSegueWithIdentifier
called perform segue with identifier.
这里 我指定 Show Photo
And here I press, specify show photo.
注意 我要指定一个 sender
And notice I get to specify a sender.
这个 sender 从哪进来
Okay, where does this sender come in?
我要在代码中执行的这个 segue
Well, this segue that I'm going to perform, in code here,
还是需要 prepareForSegue 这是普通的 push segue
still gets prepared for segue, it's a normal push segue
它有常规的 prepareForSegue
so it has to prepare for segue
记得 prepareForSegue 吧 它需要一个 sender
and if we remember prepare for segue, it takes a sender.
这个 sender 是什么呢
And what is that sender?
在表格视图控制器的情形中
Well, in the table view controller case,
sender 是表格视图单元格
remember the sender is the table view cell.
这里 sender 是什么呢
So what would we want the, the sender to be here?
或许应该是这个 annotation 视图
Probably this annotation view.
这里的 annotation 视图
This annotation view, right here,
也就是附属视图的对话框所在的 annotation 视图
is the annotation view that has the call out that we tapped that accessory view in,
这就说明了 我们讨论的是哪个 annotation
so that's going to tell us which annotation we're talking about, right?
这就是我们在 prepareForSegue 时需要的 sender
So that's the sender that we're going to see
when we go do prepare for segue for this thing.
好 下面来看 prepareForSegue 因为这是普通的 segue
Alright, so let's do the prepare for segue because this is a normal segue.
它需要准备 同其它 segue 一样
It has to be prepared, just like all the rest of the segues
要做到这个 我打算做表格视图中类似的事
that we have, and to do that, I'm going, just like I did
这里我有一小段准备代码
in table view, I'm, I have a little prepare here,
在这里 这个准备
which is right here, and this prepare kind
会准备这个地图视图控制器
of generally will prepare this map view controller
让它能 segue 到一个图像视图控制器
to segue to an image view controller.
同另外一个很类似
And it looks a lot like the other one, okay, here I'm going
这里我要检查我们要准备的 annotation 是否…
to find out if the annotation that we're going to prepare,
我们要为视图控制器做准备
so we're going to prepare for view controller, this is going
这是图像视图控制器
to be an image view controller,
进行特定 segue 显示特定 annotation
to do a certain segue to show a certain annotation.
这个应该是 Photo 我只能处理 Photo
And this had better be a photo, because that's all I know how to do.
这里检查确保它是 Photo
So I'm checking here to make sure it's a photo.
如果是 然后我再检查标识符
And if it is a photo, then I'm going to check the identifier,
同表格视图一样 如果没有标识符
same thing with table view, if there's no identifier,
那么如果类是图像视图控制器类
then if the kind of class, is an image view controller class,
那么我就 segue 到它
then I'm going to segue to it.
我等下会在 prepareForSegue 中调用这个
So this, I'm going to call this from prepare for segue in a second.
让我导入图像视图控制器
Let me go ahead and import image view controller.
这样就不会有警告了
Just so you don't have the warnings there.
大家都理解这段代码是做什么的了吗
So, everyone understand what this code does?
出于时间考虑 这里我没有一行行敲
Well I do the code significance for speed,
但我需要确保你们理解了这里的所有代码
but I want to make sure you understand all the code that appeared there.
下面我们要做的是 prepareForSegue 这很简单
Alright, so now we can do the prepare for segue and it's going to be pretty easy.
(void) prepareForSegue
So void, prepare for segue.
prepareForSegue 中 sender 是那个 MKAnnotationView
And in prepare for segue, the sender is that MK annotation view.
我们从 MKAnnotationView 知道
Alright? So we know from that MK annotation view
它是哪个
which thing it is,
这里我只需要说 如果 sender 是一个 MKAnnotationView
so I'm just going to say if the sender is an MK annotation view,
它显然应该是 那么我就
which it should be, okay, then I'm going
调用上面这里我写的准备代码
to call this prepare thing, that I did up here,
这个 prepareViewController
this prepare view controller.
prepareViewController
Prepare view controller.
这里我要准备的视图控制器是
And the view controller I'm going to prepare is
segue.destinationViewController
segue dot destination view controller.
forSegue 这里是 segue 的标识符
The segue is the segue's identifier.
而我们要显示的 annotation 是什么
And the annotation we're going to show is what?
annotation 是这个 sender
The annotation is this sender,
这是一个 MKAnnotationView
which is an MK annotation view,
这是它的 annotation
it's its annotation,
MKAnnotationView 有一个属性叫 annotation
so MK annotation view has a property called annotation,
返回的是 id MKAnnotation
which returns to the ID MK annotation that,
也就是这里我们要的
which is we want here,
也就是 MKAnnotationView 所显示的
that that MK annotation view is showing.
因此我这里说 MKAnnotationView sender annotation
So I'm going to say MK annotation view, sender, annotation.
理解吗
Make sense?
这样我们就能在对话框附属视图被点时执行 segue 了
So, we make it so we perform the segue, when we call out accessory is tapped,
那个发生时 prepareForSegue 会被调用
prepare for segue's going to get called when that happens,
我们会调用这个来做实际的准备
and we're going to call this thing to do the actual preparation,
检查确保我们考虑的是照片
checking to make sure we're talking about photos,
确保我们 segue 到的是图像视图控制器
making sure we're segueing into an image view controller.
大家都明白了吗
Everybody got that?
好 看看这能否工作
Alright, so let's see if that works.
好 点这个人
Okay, so let's go to this guy.
在世界地图上拖动
This is our world traveler here.
点下面这里
Let's go click down here.
它有这个 这里有很漂亮的图像视图
It's got this, it's got a nice image view here.
点击这个 这就 segue 了
Let's try and click on this, and it segues.
这是同原来一样的 segue
And we'll get the exact same kind of segue we got before.
理解了吗
Make sense?
这方面有问题吗
Questions about that?
好 这非常棒 体现在
Alright. So that's really pretty awesome in, you know,
只花了 20-25 分钟的时间
about 20 minutes, or 25 minutes we were able
我们就将地图能力添加到了 iPhone 版程序
to add full map capability to our iPhone version.
iPad 版又怎么样呢
But what about our iPad, our iPad version?
让我们把手机关闭 来做 iPad 版
Let's turn off my phone here, and go do the iPad version.
iPad 应该会和这里有所不同
So the iPad probably wants to be slightly different than this.
不过最开始会非常类似
Although I'm going to start off having it be very similar.
iPad 中 我将删除
What I'm going to do in the iPad is I'm going to get rid
这个拍照者表格和 PhotosByPhotographer 表格
of this photographer's table and photos by photographer table.
删除这个后
So I'm just going to delete that,
我将复制粘贴这里我做的这些
and I'm going to copy and paste what I just did, here, in this one.
复制 到这里 粘贴
Copy, over here, paste.
control 拖动
Let's control, drag.
push segue
Push segue,
抱歉 这个拆分视图控制器的根视图
or sorry, root view of this split view controller.
让我们找到所有东西
Let's go find everything.
腾出更多空间
Make some more space.
这里
There it is.
下面我们要和原来做一样的事
So now we're going to do the exact same thing we did before.
这里有拍照者 这里还会有地图
We got the photographers here and we're going to have the maps here.
首先看看这是怎样的
So let's go see what that looks like, at first.
这个能工作吗
Is this working?
哦 等等 我们需要… 抱歉
Oh, wait, we're going to have to, sorry.
这里我们需要停下来
We're going to have to stop here
因为我们会崩溃
because we are going to crash
因为我们改变了我们的数据库 schema
because we changed our database schema.
删掉这个
So let's get rid of that.
再次运行
Run again.
问题是 如果现实世界中
Okay, so the question is if I were in the real world
我在 App 商店中的 app 改变了 schema
and I had apps on the app store here and I changed my schema
我的用户更新时如何处理这个
and my users upgrade, how would I handle that?
答案是 我们没有教这个
And the answer is, and we don't teach this because, you know,
因为时间有限
you know how it is, time constraints,
实际有一个机制能对 schema 进行版本控制
but there's actually a mechanism for versioning your schema
然后从之前版本能够自动迁徙
and then doing auto-migration from previous versions,
从之前版本获得数据 转给新 schema
getting the data out of a previous version to the new schema.
schema 需要以一种可兼容的方式进行变化
So you have to change your schema in a compatible way,
显然 你不希望失去所有用户信息
obviously you want to keep all your user information,
这种迁徙可以是自动的
but that migration can be automated.
这非常酷
So it's pretty cool actually.
具体的可以到 Core Data 说明文档中查看
So, check it out in the core data documentation, how to do it.
这是我们的拍照者 如果点击一位拍照者
Alright, so here's our photographers, and if I click on a photographer,
很好 我能得到地图
then awesome, I get the map.
如果点击这些 它还是能够很好地工作
And if I click on these, woo, that work, this is just awesome, it works great.
再来尝试展示照片
Let's try and show the photo.
啊哦 为什么无法工作
Uh oh. Why doesn't that work?
因为这里在它在执行 segue
Because it's doing perform segue here.
而 iPad 上我们不使用 segue
And we don't use a segue on the iPad,
我们只需要到 detail 中的图像视图控制器直接更新
we just go find the image view controller in our detail and update it directly, right?
这里对于地图 我们需要和之前处理表格时
So we have to do the same fix we did when we made this work on,
做相同的修正
with the tables, we got to do the same thing with the map.
回到我的地图视图控制器
So, I'm going to go back, back to my map view controller.
这里
Right here.
我将放一个属性到这里
And I'm going to put some, I'm going to put a property in here
找到我所处的拆分视图 detail 中的图像视图控制器
that finds an image view controller in the detail of a split view I'm in,
如果有一个的话
if there's one there.
调用这个图像视图控制器
Call this image view controller.
这是我要添加的属性
And here's the property I'm going to add.
这个属性将为 nil
Right? So this property is going to be nil
如果拆分视图 detail 中不存在图像视图控制器
if I'm not in a split view controller where my detail is in image view controller.
否则 那就是那个图像视图控制器了
Right? Otherwise, it's going to be that image view controller.
这段代码在表格视图中有过 记得吧
Ya'll recognize this code from our table view, right?
拆分视图控制器最后一个对象 这是我们的 detail
Split view controller last object, that's our detail.
如果它处在导航控制器中
If it's in a navigation controller,
我要看看它是不是根视图控制器
I'll look in to see if it's the root view controller.
如果它是一个图像视图控制器 我就会返回它
And then if it's a view controller, an image view controller, I'll return it.
否则 nil
Otherwise nil.
在 iPhone 上 这将是 nil
So on the iPhone this is going to be nil,
因为 iPhone 上不会有拆分视图
because it can't be a split view on the iPhone anyway, right?
这很酷
So this is cool.
现在我知道 是否有一个图像视图控制器
So now I know whether there is an image view controller,
我可以做点什么 例如在我做那个 segue 时
so I could do something, for example, when I'm doing that segue,
那个 segue 在哪里
where's that segue?
这里 这个执行 segue
Right here, this perform segue.
我可以说 如果我有一个图像视图控制器
I could say if I have an image view controller,
那么就直接更新它
then just update it directly, directly,
否则 你可以尝试这个执行 segue
otherwise, you can try this perform segue.
顺便说下 没有办法
By the way, there's really no way
在尝试这个执行 segue 时不崩溃
to try this perform segue without crashing.
你需要知道 你实际在 segue
So you really got to know whether you're actually segueing.
很幸运 如果我有一个图像视图控制器
Luckily, here, if I have an image view controller around,
我知道我不会是在 segue
I know I'm not going to be segueing,
如果我没有图像视图控制器
and if I don't have an image view controller around,
我可能就要 segue 了
I probably do want to be segueing, because I got
因为我需要设法展示照片 如果我要允许
to show the photos somehow, if I'm going to allow that, the,
那个小按钮在那里
that little button to be there.
如果我有这个 self.imageViewController
So if I have this self-image view controller here,
我可以准备它
I can just prepare it.
我要准备控制器
So we've got this prepare controller,
我要准备图像视图控制器 segue 是 nil
I'm going to prepare the image view controller, segue is nil.
annotation 想要显示什么呢
The annotation, what, where does the annotation want to show,
还是一样 它在这里
again, it's right here.
view.annotation
View dot annotation.
这是这个
So there's that.
我要准备这个图像视图控制器 如果它在那里
Okay, so I'm just going to prepare that image view controller if it's there,
否则我们就 segue
otherwise we'll segue.
都理解了吗
Everyone understand this?
我们来看看这个
So let's go look at this.
看这个如何工作
See how this works.
我们还是看看某些照片
Alright, so let's look at some photos again.
我要找一些照片 像是… 我不知道这里都有谁
I'll find some photos like, I don't know who we got here,
这个人吧 我们得到这些
this guy, so we got this.
点这个
Click this.
我们得到这个
We got this right here.
点这个小按钮 能行
If I click this little button, it worked.
它使用了那个东西 如果我到这里别处
So it uses the thing, if I go over here somewhere else,
我们来选这个
let's do this guy right here.
注意到这里重叠了
Notice that overlaps, I don't really
我不大喜欢这个 UI 不过它就是这样了
like that UI very much, but it is what it is.
这基本上就好了
So that's kind of okay.
这个 UI 已经不错了 只是还不那么完美
This is kind of okay, this UI, it's really not that great though because I'm showing
这里我们有个缩略图 我点它
that little thumb nail there and then I'm, I click on it,
再显示大图
I'm also showing the big one.
我们干嘛不干脆不要缩略图
Why don't I just not have a thumb nail,
不要蓝箭头 而是每次点大头针直接显示照片
not have the little blue arrow, and every time I click on a pin, just show the photo.
没有理由不直接显示照片
There's no reason not to just show the photo.
怎么做呢
So how would I do that?
忘掉这个蓝色小箭头吧
So just forget this whole thing with that little blue arrow,
我们不再需要它
you don't even need that blue arrow.
让我们这样做
Let's do that.
到上面这里
Let's go up here to,
这是我们创建左右附属视图的地方
this is where we build the left and right accessory views, right here.
这里我说 如果我没有一个图像视图控制器
So I'm going to say if I don't have an image view controller,
那就把那些对话框放到那里
then go ahead and put those call outs in there.
否则不要把它们放到那里
Otherwise don't put them there.
而且 现在对话框不在那里
And then also, now that the call outs are there, aren't there,
这个永远也不会被调用
this is never to get called, in here,
因为不会有对话框附属视图
because there's no call out accessory
如果我有图像视图控制器
if I have the image view controller.
让我们把这些剪切掉
So let's go ahead and cut this out of here,
把这些代码放到选择中
and let's put that code in select.
这是被选择的地方
So here's where it's selected.
被选择时 我们就要
So when it's selected, let's go ahead and
视图控制 更高一些
views control higher,
哦不 这个不行
woop, nope, that didn't work.
control I 好了
Control I, there we go.
大头针被选中后 当我们点大头针时
Alright. So when the pin is selected, when we click on the pin,
如果我有一个图像视图控制器
if I have an image view control around,
我就会准备它
I'll just prepare it.
否则 我会更新对话框附属视图这些
Otherwise, I will update the call out accessory views and all
如果有图像视图控制器 这些我就都没有了
that stuff, which I don't have if I have an image view controller.
看看这是怎样的
So let's see what this looks like.
好 我们点击这里
Okay. So, no. Let's click again here.
这里将有多张照片
And it's going to be a multiple, oops, multiple photo.
我们点击一个
Okay, so, let's click on one here.
我一点 它就会立刻自动更新图像视图
Alright, automatically, as soon as I click on it, it's going to update the image view.
这很酷
So that's kind of cool.
这个 UI 更好 我不再需要缩略图
That's a nicer UI. I don't really need that thumb nail.
我也不需要其它东西
I don't need the, the other stuff on there.
这很酷
So that's cool.
不过这里有一点很奇怪 看这里
One thing though that's a little weird on it is watch this.
如果我到这里
So now if I go here.
现在我有了 deadmanjones 的照片
Now I've got dead man Jones, his photos,
但右边还有别人的照片
but I've got somebody else's photo on the right.
这很奇怪 这是糟糕的 UI
That's kind of weird. Okay, that's kind of a bad UI.
每次显示某拍照者的照片时
So let's make it so that every time we show the photos
我们可以自动选一张
by a photographer, let's just autopick one.
怎么做呢
How would we do that?
很简单
Very simple.
在 updateMapViewAnnotations 这里
When we update our view, map view annotations here,
我只需要自动选择照片
I'm just going to autoselect a photo.
不过这只在周围有图像视图控制器的前提下才行
But only in the case where I have an image view controller lying around.
如果周围有图像视图控制器 那我就要自动选照片
If I have an image view controller lying around, then I'll autoselect a photo.
如何自动选择呢
And how am I autoselecting?
可以从 PhotosByPhotographer 数组中抓取第一个对象
Well, I'm just grabbing the first object out of our photos by photographer array.
如果有的话 我将选择那个 annotation
And if there's any in there, then I'm going to select that annotation.
这会让对话框出现
That causes that call out to appear, but it doesn't,
但选择它时 它不会调用
when you select it with this, it doesn't call
上面这里的 didSelect 方法
that did select method up here to get called.
上面这个方法 didSelectAnnotationView
This method, up here, did select annotation view,
这个只在用户选择时才会被调用
this only gets called when the user selects it.
这里用户没有选择它 我们选择了它
So the user didn't select it here, we selected it,
这样我们就仍然需要准备自身
so we still have to do that prepare ourself.
我们来看看这个
Let's take a look at that.
让我们选某个人
Alright. So let's pick somebody here.
点这个 摩托车这个是自动选的
Click on that, and you can see it autoselected the scooter one,
选择别的 到这里 还是自动选择
I picked something else, we'll go here, it autoselects one.
到这里 还是自动选择
It goes here and autoselect one.
这样我们就让左右两边保持同步了
So now we're kind of all in sync between the two, between what's
on the right and what's on the left.
点另一个 它就会变化
But if I click another one, it'll change it.
这个 UI 很不赖
So that's not a bad UI.
我蛮喜欢它
I kind of, kind of like it, it's kind of okay,
不过我还打算讲另一种在 iPad 上做这个的方法
but I'm going to show you another way to do this on the iPad,
给你们展示 embed segue
to show you the embed segues.
有人可能会争辩 是这个 UI 好 还是嵌入那个好
One could argue whether this is a better UI or the embedded one,
你可以都看看
you can kind of see them both
自己判断哪个更好
and you can tell me what you think is better.
这里我打算这样
But what I'm going to do is,
看到太阳在照片中的什么地方了吗
you see where the sun is right there, in that photo?
我打算取左侧的地图视图
I'm actually going to take this map view that's on the left,
把它嵌入到这个图像视图中
and I'm going to embed it inside this image view.
地图视图会被显示到这里
So this map view is going to showing there,
这一栏我们将只会看到拍照者
and so what we're going to see in this column is just the photographers,
这些会是拍照者
these will be photographers.
太阳所在的地方
Embedded where the sun is
将嵌入我们选择的拍照者所对应的地图
will be the map for whatever photographer we choose
然后是我们的照片
and then we'll have our photo,
我们还是能缩放和拖动
and we'll still be able to zoom in our photos, zoom around,
地图会在照片上 不过我们可以加一个按钮
it'll be occluded, right? It'll be covered up, although maybe we could add a button
方便隐藏地图或是重新显示
somewhere that would hide that map and reshow it,
放到 URL 旁边 因为那个地图
a little bar next to the URL, because that map,
只是一个 UIView 我们可以隐藏它
it's just going to be a UI view, in there, we can hide,
设置它为.hidden 我们可以采用动画 透明度
set it to dot hidden, we could animate it, transparency,
淡出 怎么做都行 因为它只是 UIView
fading away, whatever we wanted to do because it's just going to be UI view.
但那个 UIView 的内容
But the contents of that UI view are going
将同这个地图视图中的内容完全相同
to be the same contents that are in this map view over here, exactly the same.
我将使用完全相同的视图控制器
I'm going to use that exact same view controller.
这里我们说的还是视图控制器再利用
And this is, again, we're talking about view controller reuse.
我们来做这个
So, let's go ahead and do that.
顺便说下 代码中有一个警告在这里
By the way, we noticed we have warnings back in the code here.
为什么会有警告呢
Why do we have this warning?
因为自动选择的照片是一个 Photo *
That's because autoselected photo is a photo star,
我们没有导入任何东西来告诉这段代码
and we don't import anything here that tells this code
Photo * 是 MKAnnotation
that a photo star is an MK annotation.
因此 上面这里导入 Photo 的地方
So we have to go up here to where we import a photo,
需要改成导入 Photo+Annotation
and instead import photo plus MK, or sorry, plus annotation.
因为这个才是
Because this is where, this is the file
我们声明 Photo 是 MKAnnotation 的文件
in which we declared that photos were MK annotations.
大家理解吗
Everyone understand that?
你需要导入定义了这个的接口
Okay, so you got to make sure you import whichever interface defines that.
好 如何做这个嵌入的东西呢
Okay. So how are we going to do this embed thing?
来到这里的 iPad 故事板
Let's go over here to our iPad, storyboard, all I'm going to do
我首先只需要拖动嵌入的东西到这里
to start is to drag an embedded thing in here, so let's do that.
屏幕空间有限 这是相当大的挑战
This is a bit of a challenge when it comes to screen real estates.
到这里
Let's go here.
嵌入的东西在很下面这里
So the embedded thing, it's down towards the bottom, here it is right here.
这里说是容器视图 定义了一个视图控制器区域
You see it says container view defines a region of view controller
能够包含一个子视图控制器
that can include a child view controller.
我要把它拖入到这里的视图控制器中
So I'm going to drag that into this view controller right here,
这是我们的图像视图控制器
this is our image view controller,
拖入进来
so let's drag that in.
拖入进来后 我们不大方便
Now when you drag this in, it's a bit of a pain in the neck
设置大小和位置这些
to size this to where you want and all those things,
不过我会展示另一种方式
but I'll show you another way,
当你有一个这样的大视图 你要拖入
when you have a big view like that, that you're dragging in
你希望把它放到什么地方
and you want to place it somewhere to do it,
你可以使用文档大纲
which is use the document online.
这是文档大纲 这是我的容器
So here's the document outline, here's my container.
注意到 它是作为滚动视图的子视图添加的
Notice it added it as a subview of my scroll view,
我不希望地图到处滚动 我希望它
but I don't want to scroll that map around, I want it to sit
定在滚动视图的顶部
on top of the scroll view,
我希望滚动视图在后面 然后是容器视图
I actually want the scroll view in the back, and then the container view,
然后再做活动指示器
and then we can do our activity indicator.
这是我可以做的一件事 也就是把它移出滚动视图
So that's one thing I can do is move it out from being a scroll view.
有没人能想到
And can anyone think of a way
如何把这个容器放到我想要的地方
that I can place this container where I want?
一个单词 用 A 开头
Magic word, begins with an A?
下面这里
Down here?
对 我们可以使用自动布局
Yes, we can use autolayout.
指定我们要的东西
Right? To specify exactly what we want.
修正它的宽度和高度
So let's fix its width and height.
这里我们需要一些固定的宽度和高度数字
This is a case where we would want some magic numbers of width
因为我们需要确定
and height, because we want to kind of decide how much
视图遮住地图上多大的区域
of that view we want to occlude with the map,
相对值是多少 然后我们还要把它固定在顶部
what the relative value is, and then let's also pin it to the top,
通过标准值 然后这边再固定到右边
by the standard value, and then let's pin it over here to the right,
这就把它放到了右上角
so we're going to put it in the upper right-hand corner.
先看看这是怎样的
And let's see what that looks like, first of all,
注意这里有个黄色的小东西
and notice we have the little yellow thing here.
因为我们错放了视图 我来修正一下这个错位
Because we have a misplaced view, and so I'm going to go ahead and fix that misplacement.
下面来看这是怎样的
And now let's go look and see how this looks like.
这同我要的还有点差距 因为这里
Eh, it just doesn't quite look like I want, because it's
它在这个栏下面 我不想要这样
under this bar, I don't really want it under this bar,
离顶部是标准宽度 不过却在栏下面
so it's a standard width from the top, but under this bar.
顺便说下 控制这些东西在不在栏下面
The way you can, by the way, control whether things are under the bar
可以选择整个控制器 进入检查器
is select your whole controller and inspect it.
下面这里可以看到扩展边缘
And you'll see down here, there's extend edges.
这里我可以把在顶栏下的勾勾去掉
So if I say under top bars, no,
这时 容器就可以移下来了
then it moves that container down.
这里创建了一些自动布局的东西
Now that created some autolayout things,
对这个小转轮和这个都是如此 我们修正一下
both for this little spinner guy and this, so let's fix those.
因为一切都往下移了一些
Right? Because we moved everything down a little bit,
这些需要被放回到应该的相对位置
so those need to be put back relatively to where they should be.
这是这个的做法
So that's a way to do it. Now, of course,
显然 图像视图不在这下面
now the image view is not under there,
我可能希望一者 而非另一者
and I might want one and not the other,
我们当然可以按自己的想法设置自动布局约束
and we can certainly set our autolayouts constraints to whatever we want,
这里我只想演示这个扩展边缘的东西
but I just wanted to show you this extend edges thing.
有些人之前在做作业时就发现了这个
Some of you discovered this when you were doing your homework before.
好 通过所有这些
So, okay. One thing that happened through all of this,
我们的得到了这个容器 我们还需要指定
we got this container, is we have to specify
容器中有些什么
what's in this container,
它实际会把某个东西放到这里
and it actually put something on here.
很难看到 移下来一些
It's hard to see, let's move it down.
这是一个通用 UIViewController
It actually put this, this is a generic UI view controller,
在检查器中 可以看到它是通用 UIViewController
if we inspect it, you can see it's a generic UI view controller.
这个视图控制器的 self.view 会出现在这里
So this view controller, self dot view, is going to appear in here.
但我不希望这个视图控制器的 self.view 在这里
But I don't want this view controller, self dot view, in here.
我打算删掉这个
So I'm going to delete that.
我想要这个视图控制器的 self.view
Instead, I want this view controller's self dot view,
地图视图控制器 对吧
the map view controller, right?
怎么做呢
So how do I do that?
这是一个 segue
This is a segue,
control 拖动
control, drag.
从容器 control 拖动到这里
So I'm control, dragging from the container to here,
唯一的选项是嵌入
only option I'm going to have is embed,
因为来自这个容器
because the source of this is the container,
这样我就把那个嵌入到了这里
and now I've embedded that in there.
我不再需要这个 segue
I don't want this segue anymore,
因为在选择拍照者时
because I don't want when, I choose the photographer,
我不希望加载这个表格 我们删掉它
I don't want to load this table up, so let's get rid of that.
现在我们有了这个 让我们把它移下来
And so now, we have this here, let's move it down again.
这个 PhotosByPhotographer 地图视图将出现在这里面
So this photos by photographer map view is going to appear inside here.
这是一个 segue
Now this is a segue, okay,
或许我们可以称这个为 Embed Map
maybe we would call this embed map
诸如此类 因为这就是 segue 的作用
or something like that, because that's what this segue does.
这个 segue 需要准备 同其它 segue 一样
This segue has to be prepared, just like any other segue,
这是一个常规的 segue
this is a normal segue.
谁来做准备呢
Who's going to do the preparing?
做准备的是这个会嵌入到的视图控制器
Well, it's the view controller into which this is embedded.
也就是这个
That is this.
这是一个图像视图控制器
Which is an image view controller.
这个 PhotosByPhotographer 需要如何准备呢
How does this photos by photographer need to be prepared?
它需要拍照者
It needs the photographer, right?
这是它的公共 API 提醒一下你们 这里
That's its public API, just to remind you, over here,
PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
photos by photographer map view controller,
需要一个拍照者
needs a photographer.
准备时 我们需要传入拍照者
So if we're going to prepare it, we need to pass the photographer.
这是一个问题 因为这个图像视图没有拍照者
Well, that's a problem, because this image view doesn't have the photographer.
图像视图只有图像
All the image view has is the image.
因此 我们需要创建一个图像视图控制器的子类
So we're going to have to create a little subclass of image view controller,
命名为 PhotosByPhotographerImageViewController
which I'm going to call photos by photographer, image view controller,
它会将拍照者传过来
and it's going to pass the photographer on through.
我们将 segue 到它
So we're going to segue to it,
就像我们已经 segue… 这其实并不是真正的 segue
like we are already segueing, it's not really segueing,
不过我们在设置这个 detail 视图控制器
but we're setting this detail view controller,
我们已经准备好了
we're preparing already,
不过准备需要用到这个拍照者
but we're going to have to prepare it with this photographers.
让我们创建这个控制器的子类
So let's create that subclass with this controller.
它是图像视图控制器的子类
Okay. It's a subclass of image view controller,
名为 PhotosByPhotographerImageViewController
we're going to call it photos by photographer image view controller.
同其它控制器放到一起
Okay. We'll put it with our controllers.
现在仅在 iPad 中 我将修改这个
Now in the iPad only, I'm going to change this
让它不再是图像视图控制器
to not be an image view controller anymore,
而是 PhotosByPhotographerImageViewController
I'm going to change it to be a photos by photographer image view controller.
现在 它是 PhotosByPhotographerImageViewController
So now it's a photo by photographer image view controller,
也就是这个
which is this thing.
这个的公共 API 还是和
The public API of this, again, it's the same
所有其它 PhotosByPhotographer 一样 也就是这个
as all these other photos by photographer, it's this,
看这个 复制这个 粘贴过来
actually watch this, we'll copy this, and we'll paste that,
放到这里 放到这里 删掉这个
put that there, put that there, get rid of that,
这样就可以了
see it going back and forth too much.
它有一个拍照者 它是一个 PhotosByPhotographer
So it has a photographer, it's a photos by photographer,
不过这是一个图像视图控制器 因此它有一个拍照者
but this is an image view controller, so it has a photographer.
它在获得拍照者时会做什么呢
What does it do when it gets the photographer?
我们来看看
Well let's look at that.
实际上 在看这个之前 我们先谈谈那个 embed segue
In fact, before we even look at that, let's talk about that embed segue and,
并为它做好准备
and having it prepare.
代码在这里 我们可以看看
So I got that code here so we can look at it.
放到这上面 马上我就会讲到
I'm going to put this up here, talk about all this in a second here,
导入 PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
and I'm going to import photos by photographer map view controller.
我们来看看这段代码
Alright, so let's look at this code that comes in.
这是 PhotosByPhotographerImageViewController
So this is photos by photographer image view controller.
它现在正尝试处理那个嵌入的准备
It is, right now, trying to handle preparing that embed.
它准备的是这个 segue
So it's preparing this segue right here.
它在对这个 segue 做准备
Its doing the prepare on this segue.
如何做到的呢
How is it doing that?
它会去检查
Well, it's looking to see
目标视图控制器是不是
if the destination view controller
PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
is a photos by photographer map view controller,
这里应该是 因为这就是我们嵌入的
which it should be, that's what we're embedding.
PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
Right? Photos by photographer map view controller,
如果是 那它就会设置拍照者
and if it is, then it's going to set the photographer.
很明显
Completely obvious, right?
它会把它设为 self.photographer
And it's setting it to self dot photographer,
也就是 PhotosByPhotographerImageViewController
that's this method right here in photos by photographer
的这个方法
image view controller.
这很好
That's all good.
不过注意 我还抓住了
But notice also I'm grabbing a hold
这个 PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
of this photos by photographer map controller.
为什么我要抓住这个不放
Why am I grabbing a hold of this thing?
抓住这个不放是因为
Well I'm grabbing a hold of this because
这个的调用可能会发生在
this might get called before
这个被调用之前
this gets called.
换言之
In other words,
在 PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
before my image view controllers, photos by photographer image view controller,
获得其拍照者之前
gets it photographer,
它可能被要求 segue 到嵌入的那个
it might be asked to segue to the embedded one,
它可能还没有这个拍照者
and it might not have this photographer yet.
因此我们需要到这里 在 setPhotographer 中
So we need to go here, in our set photographer,
这个我们总会做
which we always do this anyway,
写 self.title = photographer.name 这些东西
things like self dot title equals photographer dot name and stuff like that.
这里 我们需要…
We, here, we need to,
如果我们在嵌入后到这里 那么
if we get here after we've embedded, then we need
我们需要说 self 点地图视图控制器点拍照者
to say self dot map view controller photographer
等于我们的拍照者
equals our photographer.
这和之前我讲的一样
So this is the exact same thing we're talking
之前我说 准备可以发生在设置之前
about for prepare can happen before the setting,
设定可以发生在之后 如此往复
setting can happen after, you know, back and forth, so,
我需要在两个地方都这样做
but I have to do it in both of these places.
理解吗
Does that make sense?
好 这次我看到更多人点头了 这很好
Good, now I'm seeing more nodding heads this time and that's good.
我讲幻灯片时 很多人都一头雾水
Because when I talked about it in the slides you were like huh?
但现在你们懂了
Okay, but now you understood.
如果我们在被要求准备嵌入之后设置好模型
If we set our model after we are asked to prepare that embed,
那么我们就需要回头设置拍照者
then we have to go back and set the photographer.
最后 我们需要为这个做准备
Now the last thing we need to do is do the preparing of this guy now.
这个需要准备 它是 detail 视图控制器
This guy needs to be prepared, it's the detail view controller,
属于拆分视图
right, of this split view.
这时 我们点拍照者这里时
And so now when we click in the photographer's thing,
我们需要准备这个 通过将拍照者传递给它
we need to prepare this guy by passing him the photographers.
这也很简单
So that's really easy too.
这是我们准备的地方
Here's where we prepare, right?
在拍照者表格视图 我们知道如何准备
So right now, in our photographers table view, we know how to prepare
PhotosByPhotographer Core Data 表格视图
the photos by photographer core data table view.
我们还知道如何准备
We know how to prepare the photos
PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
by photographer map view controller,
现在我们又知道了如何准备
and now we know how to prepare the photos
PhotosByPhotographerImageViewController
by photographer image view controller, as well.
准备方式完全相同
We prepare them all exactly the same way, right?
不过目标视图控制器不同
But they're all different destination view controllers.
让我们导入 除掉这个
So let's import, make that go away,
PhotosByPhotographerImageViewController
photos by photographer image view controller,
现在就可以运行了
and now we can run.
好 可以看到美国的地图
Okay. So you can see our map, comes up the United States,
我们还没有选拍照者 因此这里没有照片
we haven't chosen a photographer, so there's, there's no photos in there.
让我们选一个拍照者
Let's pick a photographer.
这个人
This guy.
这是我们的地图 我们可以看到这在什么地方
Here's our map, we can kind of see where in the world we are.
看起来我们是在台北
Looks like we are in Taipei.
显示的是骑摩托车的人
And it's showing the scooter thing.
点另一个 我们得到这个
If I click on the other one, we get that one.
这是一个很不同的 UI
So this is quite a different kind of UI,
这里还是可以放大缩小 地图还是可以到处拖动
I can still zoom in and out here, I can still move this map around,
我可以旋转 可以放大
I could rotate it around, I can zoom in.
我还可以点另一个拍照者
I can click on another photographer here.
理解这是怎么工作的吗
Make sense? How that's working?
你可以争辩哪个 UI 更好
So, I mean, again, you can argue which is the better UI.
这个很酷
This one's kind of cool.
如果能在 URL 旁边有一个小按钮
I think if I had a little button up next to URL that said map,
显示有 map 如果我点击
that was maybe a little map icon and I pressed it
地图就消失和出现 那就更好了
and the map would disappear and reappear, this might be kind of cooler because
看看这个 UI 拍照者
if you look at this UI, I have my photographers
选择的照片和地图都同时显示在屏幕上
and my photos and the selected photo all on screen at the same time.
我可以放大 看我想看的东西
Alright? So I can be zooming in, looking at anything I want,
在这里点另一张照片
clicking on another photo by this guy,
换到另一个拍照者 来回操作
switching to another photographer, back and forth,
动动指尖 这些尽在掌控
all, right at my fingertips so that I don't have to, you know,
我不需要 segue 来改变事物这些
be segueing and things changing and all that.
好 今天就这些了 周一再会
Okay. That's all I have for you today, and I will see you on Monday.
周五要交作业 祝大家好运
Good luck with your homework that's due on Friday
有问题的可以来问我
and I'll be here for any questions you have.
更多内容 请访问我校官网 stanford.edu
> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.